<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Blog - brandon lucas green</title><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Blog</id><updated>2021-01-21</updated><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Blog"/><icon>https://brandonlucasgreen.comstatic/favicon.jpeg</icon><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Location_agnosticism</id><title type="text">Location agnosticism</title><updated>2021-01-21</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My life totally changed over the course of 2020 as did most people’s, but really it started that metamorphosis when I took a job that didn’t require commuting to an office. In July 2019 I was living in a smallish townhouse in a suburb of Boston, easily commutable to Wayfair’s central HQ in the bustling Back Bay neighborhood but ever-so-slightly quieter and cheaper than downtown. My first day working for Abstract was weird in a sense: I was still paying overpriced rent for a climate-controlled box, but instead of leaving, I was taking three or four hours of Zoom calls from said box. It was both urban and disappointingly disconnected. I relished the opportunity for sustained “focus time” at my desk in the tiny second bedroom Alicia and I shared as an “office,” but I still had to take a train or bus to a decent coffee shop or co-working space if I wanted to get away.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I loved the&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;underlying principles&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;of remote work (or, to be precise, distributed work): a team need not be co-located or working synchronously in order to solve great problems, and an individual can perform better in a space they control and are comfortable with. So when my wife and I decided that being near nature was more important that being near a city, we leaned further into it: we cashed out most of the equity I was extremely fortunate to have accumulated from my tenure at Wayfair and bought a house, not in a connected suburb of Boston but a rural town over an hour away from the city limits. Not in the middle of&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;nowhere&lt;/em&gt;, but twenty minutes’ drive from an interstate highway in a town offering the “right to farm.” Fortunately, we got pretty lucky with the house: not perfect but with great bones, well in the bounds of what we could afford, and in a nice, safe neighborhood over farmland next to a forest. Not everyone is so lucky or privileged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lockdowns started four months in. As I noted two weeks ago, I struggled a bit with depression and nihilism while watching the pandemic spread and our government prove incapable of the basic management of it. Nevertheless, my family was extremely fortunate to realize that, in spite of being unable to engage in “normal society,” we were able to bring important aspects of it into our home to replicate the aspects of it we missed most, like the coffee shops I used to frequent and the meals I used to crave at my favorite spots. We started FaceTiming almost weekly with our parents and siblings, and now feel closer to them than ever. I took on new hobbies (mainly centered around improving the house) and creative outlets (like writing this) to fill time previously spent at shows, bars with coworkers, and warehouse practice spaces with musician friends.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is what&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;chose to do. Not everyone thrives in a rural environment. Most important about the past year of discovery was&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;that we should all move to peace &amp;amp; quiet, but that the situation in 2021 enables us to be and have exactly what we want, pretty much anywhere — even if that somewhere is home. I didn’t attempt to replicate my old music hangs, but if I wanted to, I had the option to pretend I was at a show, courtesy of Instagram Live and Patreon and others, or in a warehouse practice space thanks to those same platforms and tools like Zoom, Twitch and JamKazam, if I so pleased. I could even sign up for&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bso.org/brands/bso/features/bso-now.aspx&#34;&gt;high-definition live performance video of my city’s symphony orchestra&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to re-live the joy of the lower balcony of Boston’s Symphony Hall. With a sub-$500 TV and surround sound system (or even a couple of HomePods), it comes damn close to the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be clear: 4K video and livestreaming are absolutely&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;a replacement for in-person entertainment... but it has closed the gap a bit. And that gap will only get smaller over time such that you won’t need to live in a major city to experience the happenings exclusive to the major city, nor will you need to move to the middle of nowhere to experience the joy of silence in nature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What is location agnosticism?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of location agnosticism is this:&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Anything I want to have or do is available at my fingertips, no matter where I am, and in the format with which I am most comfortable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not really anything new. It’s not simply about defining a methodology for remote work. It’s a values system that can govern many—or all—aspects of your life, as you see fit. It’s something you can decide is important or not to how you live your life, something that helps guide decisions around where you go and what you invest in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not an excuse for homebody-ism. Sure, I love being at and around my house, but I also get stir crazy. We all crave social interaction. I talk to my neighbors at a social distance and occasionally enjoy the light banter of my mask-covered grocery cashier. I would love to drive back into Boston’s Allston neighborhood to catch a punk show at one of my favorite former dives. In lieu of that, I have alternatives at home that are becoming increasingly compelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not something only for homeowners or rural dwellers to leverage. City dwellers obviously have their travel options too — sure, airports during a pandemic are risky, but flying sure is cheap — and options abound for bringing more of the world into a tiny apartment. Modular storage systems, convertible surfaces and even&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fernish.co/&#34;&gt;rental furniture&lt;/a&gt;, are a thing now blogged about by thousands across the Internet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesplz.coffee/&#34;&gt;Delicious coffee from around the world is something you can subscribe to&lt;/a&gt;. You can even&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ooni.com/&#34;&gt;recreate brick oven pizza&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in a 8&#39;x6&#39; kitchen if you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s not digital nomadism, either. I don’t want my possessions to be location agnostic just so I can sell my house and freely travel the world — I might’ve mentioned that I love being at home. A lot. But city-dwellers who love living in cities, or nomads who love to travel the world whenever they please, should have access to the most important things to them in their location of choice.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And in 2021 we’re quite close to that being a reality,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;not thanks to AR or VR&lt;/em&gt;, but because of some key advances in a few areas and, more importantly, the mindset shift that the pandemic forced upon many of us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Adjusting&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say what you will about the pandemic. It sucks. I know people are in survival mode. We’ve all had to adjust. People have left the major cities in droves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/greener-pastures-dont-appeal-to-all-who-left-nyc-11610463602?reflink=desktopwebshare_linkedin&#34;&gt;Some have decided they regret it, and they’re being gaslighted by the Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of focusing on ways to make it easier for the people who want to return to cities to do so, we’re forced to choose a side: urban or rural. With location agnosticism,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;why should it matter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve also talked to dozens of folks who are struggling, but innovating. I’ve watched creators shift from live to virtual performances, from sponsor-driven revenue to subscriptions paid for by their biggest fans. Jobless folks have turned to Patreon, Twitch, Substack and OnlyFans to try new forms of income — and while millions are still suffering,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/the-onlyfans-phenomenon-empowerment-vs-establishment-5167625e7b95&#34;&gt;it’s working out&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for some. I truly wish success for all these folks, not only because they deserve some amount of financial stability, but also to beg the question: how many of us really want to go back to the old way of working?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you were considered disposable by your previous employer,&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;why&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;would&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;you want to go work for them again if you didn’t need to?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;That’s a difficult mental shift, especially in America where so many of our decisions—including where to go and what to invest in—are driven by the power of massive corporations. As more individuals are able to work from anywhere, increasingly for themselves, we remove our dependence on these corporations and can introduce different values into our lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Enablers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I cannot emphasize how grateful I am for the list of innovations I am about to walk through which have expanded the possibilities for location agnosticism:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modern Apple hardware.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Between the most recent round of iPhones, iPads and the new Apple Silicon Mac lineup, there’s no reason for concern of an unreliable computing machine anymore (of course, assuming you can afford it). Each of these devices are so rock-solid for doing any kind of work on a computer – either at home or on the go. (Not that I go much of anywhere, but it’s great to know that I can work from the parking lot of my grocery store while masked.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliable virtual desktopping and intuitive automation.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;The fact that my Apple hardware is just so reliable means I can access any of it anywhere. If I’m out and about but need to grab a file from my Mac mini at home, I have multiple ways of doing that, either by logging in remotely with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://edovia.com/en/screens-ios/&#34;&gt;Screens&lt;/a&gt;, SSHing in with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/a-shell/id1473805438&#34;&gt;a-shell&lt;/a&gt;, or with one of several&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/guide/shortcuts/welcome/ios&#34;&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;I had already created for some specific cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliable noise-canceling headphones,&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;specifically (in my opinion) the AirPods Pro. If I need to step away from my family in a pinch, I can enter a world all to myself. If I need to pay attention to the world, I just hold my earbud for a quarter second and can then hear everything around me. If AirPods Pro are too costly (I know, they are), you have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B082G2RKSV/ref=cm_sw_r_cp_api_glc_fabc_CmncGb06V1D4G&#34;&gt;solid alternatives for sixty bucks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliable video collaboration.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Say how tired you are of Zoom. I don’t care — it’s near-perfect at helping people talk to each other, especially if you have reliable internet. Speaking of which,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally affordable gigabit internet.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;A year after we moved into our current house, our introductory discounted Internet offer from Comcast expired. You know what was only $8/month more expensive than the shitty default package? Gigabit download speeds. Arguably the most invaluable service I pay for other than electricity itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smarter, unified smart home technology.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;I’m able to secure my home using a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apple.com/homekit&#34;&gt;secure protocol honed by Apple&lt;/a&gt;, including a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MiguelRipoll23/homebridge-securitysystem#readme&#34;&gt;virtual alarm system I configured and manage myself that functions like an actual alarm system&lt;/a&gt;, without having to pay a creepy third party ridiculous fees to watch my house and call 911 for me. Why does this matter? If I ever want or need to leave the house, the last thing I’m worrying about is whether I’ll know if we’re getting intruders or that my dog is safe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased financial options and improved access to financial information &amp;amp; best practices.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;All this would be impossible without an increased awareness of my financial options. I am grateful for all the advice I’ve received from parents and in-laws, but I’m even more grateful to have tools like&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nerdwallet.com/&#34;&gt;Nerdwallet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.creditkarma.com/&#34;&gt;Credit Karma&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the countless budgeting apps to help me understand what I can do with my credit score and how I can manage debt.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Access to affordable food &amp;amp; health product via Amazon and other online vendors.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;An example from the past few months: We just bought a portable treadmill for $300 so Alicia could go on walks without having to risk slipping her pregnant body on ice. I remember when it was a big deal for my parents to buy a NordicTrack when I was a kid. Another example: all the gluten-free foods that are available not just in grocery stores, but on Amazon and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thrivemarket.com/&#34;&gt;Thrive Market&lt;/a&gt;, shipped to me on an automatic recurring basis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Where we could keep going&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology is enabling location-agnostic living, but there’s so much further we can go. If the pandemic doesn’t end quickly, or we find ourselves in another one soon after, there will continue to be massive investments in helping people live more of their lives at home or&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;wherever&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;they choose to be. Those investments fall into three major buckets: logistics, job creation and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Logistics&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amazon and Apple have proven that it’s possible to ship massive quantities of products worldwide in pretty quick timeframes. I already mentioned I started getting some cheap, portable exercise equipment for the house; in a matter of 3 days I had a small home gym.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shipping perishable food at scale is a really hard problem. Yet hundreds of restaurants both shifted toward takeout and delivery to sustain their business and even began selling their recipes &amp;amp; ingredients to customers. And why not? Why scour the internet for a recipe you’ll struggle to get right, or deal with the repetitive mediocrity of services like HelloFresh, when you can&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;choose&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;to get amazing food from your local restaurant of choice or have them enable a fun at-home cooking experience for you and your family? But this only goes so far: you’re location-locked. There is a decent Mexican family-style restaurant in my town, but what if I want a particular dish from this Venezuelan dive I loved in Bushwick? There’s a realistic future in which I could order the ingredients and recipe from that restaurant’s website, powered by Shopify, and have them shipped to my house four hours away. As a customer I don’t care whether they necessarily came&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;from&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;the physical restaurant location, as long as I know exactly how to recreate the amazing shredded beef arepas I so dearly miss to this day. Were they deep-fried? I don’t remember, but if so, I can get a deep fryer from Amazon in a day or two for 60 bucks — and that time to deliver will keep decreasing, even as the next pandemic triggers the next frantic search for toilet paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s harder than moving food? Moving our entire lives. A lot of people stay put not because they love where they live, but because the process of moving — let alone leasing or buying a house or apartment — is a ridiculous amount of work. The Internet has made it really easy to&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;find&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;new places to visit or live, but the process of actually moving to those locations is somehow still tedious, expensive and confusing in 2021 between open houses, inspections, the slow process due to the legal and financial burden you’re incurring. If people continue to move out of cities thanks to remote work, what if a startup were to disrupt the legal aspects of renting or buying a house? Drones and great iPhone cameras already make it easy for property managers or realtors to provide virtual tours of a house — what if you could perform a home inspection virtually, hire a property lawyer and close on your new house entirely from your old house?&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;(Sure, most of this is already technically possible, but I hope that over time, folks in legal professions will grow comfortable with new, secure document and video collaboration tools to make this possible.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I think about other places I could live in the future, I start to think of Airbnb not just as a way to vacation, but as a way to scout new places to live. I remember staying at a tiny Airbnb in Williamsburg, Brooklyn when Alicia and I considered living there for a while. We wanted to have a hipster New York weekend, but we also wanted to feel out what it would be like to live there. Imagine using the remote Airbnb cabin you book next not just as a getaway, but as a taste of what remote cabin living would look like.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if, in a few years, you could move out to a cabin in the woods and have access to pretty much all the things you had before, thanks to a process you did entirely virtually with all the transparency you’d have from an in-person real estate agent? What if you&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/greener-pastures-dont-appeal-to-all-who-left-nyc-11610463602?reflink=desktopwebshare_linkedin&#34;&gt;hated cabin living and wanted to move back&lt;/a&gt;, but you could sell your cabin and get back into a city apartment in a matter of, say, two weeks?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if you wanted to change up your furniture look for the new house, so you got all your furniture re-sold via Letgo, Poshmark and Facebook Marketplace and rented some new stuff to try via&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fernish.co/&#34;&gt;Fernish&lt;/a&gt;? What if you could plan out the entire look and feel of your home without even being there thanks to high-res 3D renderings of the home, provided to you by the previous owner or their realtor in a format even&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt;understood?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Job creation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As much as it’s likely been painful for millions of people to survive 2020 due to job loss (I am immensely privileged and lucky to not know this feeling), it’s comforting to know simply how many options exist to both educate and employ oneself, thanks to the Internet. Learning how to code is free or incredibly cheap now. Anyone can start making money by setting up an OnlyFans or Twitch account about any topic they find interesting. You could even build an entire business with a bunch of cheap online services without any coding experience; there’s an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.indiehackers.org/&#34;&gt;entire community of thousands dedicated to developing and shipping these ideas&lt;/a&gt;. I visit Indie Hackers every few weeks to skim the new ideas people are building and am constantly impressed, not necessarily with the ideas but with the diversity of folks exploring new ways to sustain a living.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s say these trends continue. We already know and embrace robots taking over many jobs previously covered by humans; I’m not about to begin complaining about retail self-checkout, self-driving cars or drones delivering my packages. Why not embrace these inevitable changes as&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;improvements&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;to our daily lives, and encourage more creation of new ideas? The beauty of these kinds of jobs is that, in most cases, they can be done from anywhere you have access to the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to talk about web SaaS Products or the business side of collaboration. Remote work will inevitably continue to improve because so many companies are simply bad about it now. The collaboration investments that will matter will help resolve the issue of isolation: the feeling of being socially present, in a shared space with others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume VR keeps advancing. I still debate whether it’ll ever be as good as sci-fi movies purport, but in the meantime, our video collaboration software and hardware is also getting better and better. I avoid Facebook as much as possible, but its Portal can already follow you around your house while you talk to the family. Imagine what Apple’s rumored AR glasses could do with FaceTime or Zoom integrated. Imagine a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rollingstone.com/product-recommendations/smart-home/best-fitness-mirror-reviews-1064555/&#34;&gt;Fitness mirror&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;but for your family gatherings or job interviews. Imagine an entire wall of your apartment that you could share with your friends in an entirely different house, seeing a virtually live feed of each other’s half of a virtual party. AR, or even a large tablet screen, could enable a near-live game of Monopoly or Catan, as if everyone is literally sitting next to each other (depending on the layout of course). We have a mostly-bare wall in our living room currently, and I get excited thinking about the virtual window it could open to, whether it be my sister’s new house, a shared coworking space with my coworkers, or the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gardnermuseum.org/&#34;&gt;Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum&lt;/a&gt;. If the video quality and proportions are right, it’ll be like I’m there, and my kitchen is three steps behind me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hilarious truth is that we’re really not far away. Fitness mirrors and live virtual classes exist. The only thing holding these things back from being truly compelling are internet speeds, picture quality and cost — each of which will improve quicker than we’ll realize.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And for some of us, it’s already good enough.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CJqu6F1gr8u/?igshid=e51xrtgdabnt&#34;&gt;This guy tried to replicate Disney World for his kids&lt;/a&gt;. Was it perfect? No, but a toddler wouldn&#39;t notice.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I often wonder how happy (or depressed) I’d be if I was alone in this house. (Of course, if I was not married, I’d probably have no reason to buy a house in rural Massachusetts and my life would look quite different). Having a spouse and dog I love, plus a child on the way, are truly the elements that made our version of location agnostic living an enjoyable way to live.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wonder how the ideas of companionship and roommates will shift as the developed world shifts. Not to say that I believe nobody should live alone — I wanted this for myself for a long time — but I wonder about the mental well-being of those living alone while respecting the seriousness of the pandemic. In TV and movies, there’s often the trope of the hacker personality living alone, endlessly staring at a computer screen or the lenses of a VR headset, as a means of coping with loneliness or social anxiety. One of my favorite all-time shows,&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/em&gt;, centers around one of these characters. I do genuinely hope that investments in virtual space-sharing will destroy this notion that we are all alone, hunched behind a screen with our pajama bottoms and hoodies on, and that’s the only way to collaborate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;On privilege, location &amp;amp; minimalism&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I wrote this, I kept thinking about how much of the concept of location agnosticism is one of luxury: so many of the decisions I noted were made possible by money I accumulated working a white-collar tech job in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/2020/12/08/boston-segregation/&#34;&gt;highly segregated city&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;as a straight white man with a liberal arts degree. Even with all that considered, our life is far from perfect, and I&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;struggle with financial insecurity. I literally have no possible means to imagine the desperation some people are facing right now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In writing this, I realized that&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;location agnosticism need not be a symbol of privilege, but rather a priority one can make for their life.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;So many of the innovations of 2020 can bring aspects of location agnosticism to more people than ever, and ultimately it&#39;s up to the individual as to how important it is to have access to your most important things, experiences, and loved ones and in what ways. One does not need next-day delivery from Amazon or quick access to an airport or a huge house to achieve a location-agnostic lifestyle. It&#39;s far more about knowing what aspects of your life are important to you, and ensuring you have the systems and tools available to get at it wherever or whenever you happen to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my case, I&#39;ve decided that a bunch of the services I used to rely on are not worth keeping. I&#39;ve stopped impulse-buying things I don&#39;t need. I&#39;ve instead learned so much about cooking and baking over the last few months, and not only can I prepare a steak in multiple ways better than the best nearby steakhouse, and my family is saving a ton of money in the process because I&#39;m using&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.butcherbox.com/&#34;&gt;meat that is delivered to my house&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;every few weeks – and I&#39;m enjoying myself learning these new things. This was one of several intentional decisions made over the past year to cut out crutches and stay focused on the values my family and I care about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pandemic obviously accelerated much of the shift to remote work, and the isolation that comes with it. I also do not expect the pandemic to go away quickly, nor do I expect it to be the only one in my lifetime. That said, I feel more prepared than ever, and I hope that some of the developments that have resulted allow us to live more flexibly&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;comfortably, in whichever way that is for a given individual. Sure, it doesn&#39;t come without a fair degree of privilege, but as innovation continues and prices go down for some of these modern conveniences, more of will be able to live in the way we desire.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Location_agnosticism"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/LinkedIn_and_creativity</id><title type="text">LinkedIn and creativity</title><updated>2021-01-08</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before I get into anything:&lt;/em&gt; I was going to post a newsletter today primarily talking about creative outlets, and then &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/01/06/us/trump-mob-capitol-building.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Spotlight&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&#34;&gt;a treasonous coup was attempted by an armed mob less than 7 hours away from my house&lt;/a&gt;. I won’t use my small platform to talk about this — there’s plenty that’s been said already by people better informed than me — but I do want to acknowledge that it feels incredibly uncomfortable to publish content from my limited, privileged point of view about trying to do better as a human when so many people in America have not only given up on doing so, but seem to now believe that ignorance and brutality are somehow the right values to pursue. Let’s hope that the people ignoring this disheartening reality have finally taken notice and their actions reflect this. There’s nowhere else to go but up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;takes a breath&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working with a leadership coach through my employer. During one of my last sessions, we got into a dialogue about what activities I use to exercise the creative muscle I won’t stop going on about. I mentioned music, as I typically do in these types of conversations, but also the fact that I’ve struggled to see it as a purely fun endeavor. I expressed my need to write &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;, and over the course of the conversation we landed on the fact that I could start writing freely in the mornings to get thoughts down, and gradually they may evolve into more concrete ideas for newsletters, fiction, whatever they may be. These ideas could come from anywhere and solely exist as manifestations of small ideas I have. I’ve had a horrible habit of &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; writing things down throughout my life — I blame my excellent memory for details for this — and through this coaching session, I discovered that this may have contributed to my inability to feel creatively accomplished as of late. To quickly report: writing almost every day since that session has helped me center my mood immensely, and I have started writing this newsletter again as a result.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At one point during the conversation, as an example of a possible use of this writing down of things, the coach interjects his own creative outlet: Using &lt;a href=&#34;http://canva.com&#34;&gt;Canva&lt;/a&gt; to create little visuals of quotes he likes, and then posting them on LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ll be candid: I reacted &lt;em&gt;viscerally&lt;/em&gt;. Almost every word in the sentence made me cringe: Canva, quotes, visuals, LinkedIn. I’ve never been a visual person. I married a designer/photographer because she complements my strengths and weaknesses, and one of those weakness is visual thought. When we think of an improvement to our home, I am usually completely unable to visualize what it will look like; I have to trust her vision (and I am usually impressed with the result). I’ve never used Canva and don’t see a reason to start — it appears to be a tool almost exclusively for designing social media posts, and the simple fact that a business can exist on that value proposition makes me want to die inside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been one to, as they say, capture quotes that inspire me. I’ve never personally felt inspired by something someone else said. In fact, quotes often feel to me like a cop-out for both original thought and careful nuance applied to a given situation. Nuance is arguably the most important element to bring to human society &amp;amp; culture in 2021; quotes and platitudes oversimplify, and as a result, lead to overly simplistic thinking and solutions to deeply complicated problems.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about LinkedIn. &lt;strong&gt;I despise it.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s the worst kind of social network: one centered around the cutthroat, fake-supportive, workaholic white-collar culture mostly bred in America (and bleeding overseas), in which professionals are directly incentivized to shamelessly spew platitudes, share mostly hollow wins that don’t improve our society, and half-heartedly congratulate their peers over all of it. Where Facebook and Twitter are cesspools of vitriol and Instagram is a scrollable billboard, LinkedIn is a virtual circle-jerk for the professional community. I don’t know whether the content shared on LinkedIn is done genuinely, but years of experience in the consumer &amp;amp; enterprise technology industry and other social media platforms have wired my brain to think that is not. &lt;strong&gt;I’m unhappy I have to use LinkedIn to get this read by people.&lt;/strong&gt; I hope you sign up for my newsletter so you don’t need to use LinkedIn to find it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Subscribe now&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Subscribe now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, for some reason, I visit it compulsively three or four times a day. My time on LinkedIn is truly a compulsion: I don’t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to go there because the content and underlying premise of LinkedIn makes me want to die but, subconsciously, something makes me do it. I think it roots to a former deep insecurity about my career prospects — I wouldn’t post, but I would seek approval and encouragement from others, or scour the job boards to consider my options. I also am reasonably certain that active contribution to the LinkedIn cesspool does in fact improve my chances of consideration for work posted on LinkedIn — that &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be part of the algorithm, because it serves everyone (especially Microsoft, who — friendly reminder — owns LinkedIn).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My coach had me thinking: Do LinkedIn users post things as a creative outlet, or to shamelessly promote themselves, or both, or something else entirely?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On another dimension: Is a creative outlet intrinsically tied to promoting one’s work, business or the desire to generate income, or can one separate those two ideas from each other?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do either of those questions even need to be answered? Obviously they don’t. Anything that one considers a creative outlet can be considered a creative outlet, even if it’s weirdly tied to a thing that helps one find or promote their work. It took me several days to understand how posting anything at all on LinkedIn — of all social networks — could be considered just a fun creative thing to do.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I don’t need to be capturing field recordings for my next piece of ambient music, or brainstorming a work of epic fiction to be “exercising my creative muscles.” I could just write. I could even write something to post on social media — which by the way, as I already mentioned, I will have done with this newsletter. It’s not about the distribution method, it’s about the ideas being explored and shared, which can be as simple as thinking about and sharing a quote you like, or as complex as a collection of carefully structured ideas set to music. I don’t need to build creativity up to something more than it is the act of creating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/linkedin-and-creativity?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/linkedin-and-creativity?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/LinkedIn_and_creativity"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Out_of_nowhere</id><title type="text">Out of nowhere</title><updated>2021-01-01</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometime around May this year, I fell into a few different forms of writer’s block: I stopped being able to write music, I mostly stopped sharing things on social media, and I stopped writing this newsletter. If you are one of the impressive nineteen people who get this post in your email inbox, firstly, thank you; also, you probably didn’t notice (which is obviously fine).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I felt uncomfortable sharing thoughts, music, opinions, really anything at all when so many people around me were suffering. 2020 was, in many ways, the year of loads of people crying out — to be heard, to be helped, to argue, to defend their beliefs and values. Not only did I not want to add to the noise, but I found myself actively resistant to the idea of participating in my largely progressive, highly privilege-driven echo chamber.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also stopped writing and talking about music after rushing out &lt;a href=&#34;http://sophomoresmusic.com&#34;&gt;my last album &lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sophomoresmusic.com&#34;&gt;Full Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; in May. I primarily wanted to just get it off my plate. I’m not proud of how it sounds — it’s a lazy production in several regards, and I didn’t care to promote it. So many of my friends needed to figure out new ways to sustain a living and it fell terrible trying to promote my own music as a person with a stable income. I did have things to say; I didn’t feel like asking people to listen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;captioned-image-container&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-268-268&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fd2366e25-4f62-461d-abbf-aa82f7897553_2645x2645.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/d2366e25-4f62-461d-abbf-aa82f7897553_2645x2645.png&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/d2366e25-4f62-461d-abbf-aa82f7897553_2645x2645.png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:268,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:6046262,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-268-268 {
            padding-bottom: 100%;
            padding-bottom: min(100%, 268px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-268-268 img {
            max-width: 268px;
            max-height: 268px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, 2020 is over and we can look forward to a still-painful-but-slightly-more-optimistic 2021 thanks to a number of developments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve also gotten over myself a bit. I realized only recently that it’s not about adding noise to the echo chamber — instead, it’s about finding something I’m genuinely excited to talk about, and talking about that thing. &lt;strong&gt;I think I was depressed for much of the early phase of the pandemic&lt;/strong&gt;. That kept me in a state devoid of joy and falling into (mostly unhealthy) patterns: complaining, doom-scrolling, doing the basic things that need getting done instead of truly taking care of myself and the few around me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure what specifically caused a turnaround for me — in reality, it was probably a number of things starting or resolving themselves (more on that later). Now I’m pleasantly surprised to be, for the first time in a while, excited and unconcerned about the future. I am aware of the privilege that has led to my own lack of worry about the future — the world around me is still pretty miserable for quite a lot of people — but I’m happy to have my mind in a good place, and from there I hope to maybe lift others a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also hope to bring some joy into the world: &lt;strong&gt;my wife and I conceived of a baby daughter, and she’s due in March.&lt;/strong&gt; If I cannot take on the world’s challenges myself, I can at least raise a good human to perpetuate some good in the world after I’m too far gone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before moving on, yes: we are having a child during a pandemic. We are also going to be having it in our home, not in a hospital. This was not a decision triggered by the pandemic, but something the pandemic reiterated the value of doing. Home birth is a completely safe and, for us, the superior option to hospital-based birth in 2020. If this at all interests you, you should do some light research on the topic and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.whynothome.com&#34;&gt;why plenty of doctors prefer it themselves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;A scattershot retelling of what happened&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time both flew by and stopped, as everyone has already felt and reported. So, in a number of ways, a lot changed, but a lot stayed the same. As the year came to an end, I found myself struggling to succinctly answer: &lt;strong&gt;what did I actually do this year?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After thinking about it for a while, I found myself amused, because quite a few really big important things did happen, starting with the aforementioned future daughter. People have written on the fact that the pandemic didn’t create, but instead accelerated, a lot of meaningful changes across the world — the shift to remote work and learning, the funding of vaccine development, the political landscape, just to mention a few — and in many ways, the same occurred. For me, remote work was not new, but I really settled into it thanks to a concerted effort across &lt;a href=&#34;http://abstract.com&#34;&gt;my company&lt;/a&gt; to embrace the realities of pandemic/remote life. Almost gone are superfluous, ritualistic meetings; what we now have (mostly) are short intentional calls, bouts of meaningful focus or personal time, and opportunities to simply socialize. Just before the December holidays, my team did a virtual Christmas cookie bake-off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I learned so much about maintaining and improving a home. I installed some flooring and an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/CHGQUIGJ5LW/&#34;&gt;entirely new staircase &amp;amp; railing&lt;/a&gt; in my house. I also planted a garden, built a garden fence, installed some smart light switches, patched a leaky concrete wall in the basement, replaced all the doorknobs in the house with modern-looking ones, learned how to use a zero-turn riding lawnmower, organized the garage a few times, and started installing a drop ceiling in my unfinished basement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I learned to simply love being home. Home cooking, drinking, relaxing, socializing, all of it. Between food allergies, health &amp;amp; life changes, and the pandemic, Alicia and I gradually grew averse to the limited going-out options we had — and replaced them with suitable alternatives in and around our home, including:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bathing Rosie and trimming her nails in our guest bathtub, a la a dog groomer (the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B075N83693/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;nail trimmers&lt;/a&gt; and additional grooming supplies cost the equivalent of, like, 2 groomer appointments);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;My wife learning to cut her own and my hair (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B088BD5SNZ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;the professional barber kit we bought&lt;/a&gt; cost the equivalent of, like, 3 haircuts);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me learning to make soups, roast vegetables and grill steaks arguably better than any nearby restaurant (if only we had a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ooni.com&#34;&gt;pizza oven&lt;/a&gt;, I’d probably have no reason to eat out ever again);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Converting one corner of our kitchen into a cute little breakfast nook resembling the coffee shop I stopped being able to visit;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leaning heavily into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chemexcoffeemaker.com&#34;&gt;Chemex pour-over coffee&lt;/a&gt; lifestyle, and having some of the best coffee I’ve ever had as a result;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Converting our never-used dining room into a fun lounge for sitting, talking, drinking cocktails and listening to records; and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turning our bedroom into a day spa, complete with relaxing chaise lounge overlooking our yard, ambient music and self-taught massage techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent roughly 2 hours of every day walking and/or playing with my adorable little monster pup Rosie. I also started exercising more, but these 2 hours always fill my Apple Watch activity rings on their own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I almost entirely weened myself off social networks as forms of entertainment and distractions. I now spend this time listening to music, watching great TV, playing with my dog, cuddling with my pregnant wife and (more recently) writing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I finally experienced the masterpiece that is &lt;em&gt;The Sopranos&lt;/em&gt;, which I put off watching for years inexplicably. I don’t love mob movies, and I assumed this was just another one spread over six seasons, but Jesus Christ was I wrong. The commentary on mental health, American crime, toxic masculinity — in many ways it was ahead of its time and very prescient in 2020. (It’s also wonderful seeing the nuances of Italian American culture I’ve experienced through my wife’s family on screen. My grandmother-in-law is basically Livia Soprano minus the sociopathy).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A job I was admittedly on-the-fence about transformed into one of my favorite jobs of my product management career. I can’t say much about why at this moment, but I’ll have more to share later in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://producttherapy.show&#34;&gt;started a goddamn podcast&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, we only did 5 episodes, but it’s something I can hang my hat on — and we’ll probably bring it back in some form next year (albeit with less direct involvement from me — thanks, future kid).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I found myself communicating with my family more than I have since I moved out of my house at 18. FaceTime chatter with my parents has become a near-weekly occurrence; I am now closer with my sister and her husband than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also ate a ridiculous amount of trail mix, which has secretly become my favorite food of 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/365-Everyday-Value-Chocolate-Carnival/dp/B07GLT818J&#34;&gt;365 brand Cherry Chocolate Carnival&lt;/a&gt;, here’s lookin’ at you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Values&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I came into the year thinking about how I can achieve &lt;strong&gt;clarity&lt;/strong&gt; on my values, and, while I didn’t necessarily accomplish the specific things I wanted to complete, I believe my values and priorities are clearer than ever thanks to the events of this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My family comes first.&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t think I truly embodied that value until the second half of this year, and with a daughter coming, I won’t compromise this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;True balance between professional and personal, and presence within each.&lt;/strong&gt; Working remotely has made this truly possible where a commute never could; bringing more of my interests into my home has enabled balance in ways I could never have imagined.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a corollary to the last point: &lt;strong&gt;location flexibility.&lt;/strong&gt; This extends beyond just “remote work” and is a value I want to publicly talk about more, as a means of enabling balance and stay closer to one’s values. Sure, many of us are working entirely at home right now — but there is no reason why we can’t make that a wonderful place to be both professionals and loving family members. It also doesn’t mean we shouldn’t be able to continue working in the same way from a campsite in the woods of New Hampshire or a coffee shop in Berlin. Expect me to write more on this subject this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalism, appropriately applied.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve learned so much this year about what my family does and does not need. This first manifested as, admittedly, an explosion of credit card debt, and I first felt deep anxiety about it. As we worked to get this under control, we made difficult calls about our priorities and what we thought was worth spending money on, and have landed on an approach of what we’re calling “minimal of quality” — we don’t need a lot, but what we need must be very good: organic food &amp;amp; clothing, reliable and purpose-built technology, and the like. We also don’t need to “go out” to enjoy ourselves (as alluded to in my ramble about loving home), but that means we aim to be intentional about what we &lt;em&gt;do &lt;/em&gt;travel for, once we can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time for and openness to new forms of creativity.&lt;/strong&gt; Music has always been my go-to-creative outlet, but it need not be the only one. Simply getting thoughts written down — no matter how unformed or crazy — has proven an effective outlet. So is noodling on a potential future product idea.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;My favorite music of 2020&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A year-end/year-start write-up would not be complete without a shortlist of the music I liked most from the past year. Will keep this short.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haim &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women In Music, Part III&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — What a wonderful collection of songs. This might be my favorite of the year. “Up From A Dream” almost single-handedly got me fascinated with bass guitar tone again, yet also served as a come-to-Jesus that I am not a good mixer/masterer of audio. That song just &lt;em&gt;sounds&lt;/em&gt; perfect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perfume Genius &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set My Heart On Fire Immediately&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — I admittedly was very late to the party of Perfume Genius, and I’m still not sure whether I like his older stuff, but Jesus this album is warm &amp;amp; inviting. I picked up this album for the first time in mid-December and I’ve had “Describe” stuck in my head pretty much nonstop since then. The density and overwhelming sense of pleasure in that song just gets me every time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad Moves &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Untenable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — I appreciated that there was some good punk rock that came out in 2020, though most of it reflected the anger and depression that most felt in 2020. I found &lt;em&gt;Untenable&lt;/em&gt; to a lot of fun in a year otherwise sparse of fun. Best track is the opener “Local Radio” — if you don’t find yourself banging your head and dancing around to it, just give up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run The Jewels &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RTJ4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — I only listened to this a few times but when I did, God, it was a gut punch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fiona Apple &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fetch The Bolt Cutters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — This album is so fun and clever. I’m honestly most disappointed that I can’t blast it in the house because my dog flips out every time she hears Fiona’s dogs audibly barking throughout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nine Inch Nails, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ghosts V: Together&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — I listened to this &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; in 2020. As more and more of my life moved into my home, and a lot of intense realities of the world and our lives came into and out of focus, &lt;em&gt;Together&lt;/em&gt; was the calm ambience that helped center me often.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Olafur Arnalds &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Kind of Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — Second-place for the album that helped center and calm me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prince &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign O’ The Times Super Deluxe Edition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; — Okay, not a new album, but the newly released tracks (plus the original, weirder version of “Strange Relationship”) make this completely interesting as a new collection of its own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2021&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s the first day of 2021 and I’m very excited about the next 364 days. I’m keeping expectations about the world around me pretty low — we’ll still be in a pandemic, it won’t go away, and I’m comfortable with that — on the other hand, I’ll have a daughter to raise, and a set of values I’m more firm on than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;captioned-image-container&#34;&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-472-644&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F270f4894-a6bb-4e7a-9072-a6d828886c84_3024x2211.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/270f4894-a6bb-4e7a-9072-a6d828886c84_3024x2211.jpeg&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/270f4894-a6bb-4e7a-9072-a6d828886c84_3024x2211.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1065,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:644,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:1652062,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-472-644 {
            padding-bottom: 73.14560439560441%;
            padding-bottom: min(73.14560439560441%, 471.0576923076923px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-472-644 img {
            max-width: 644px;
            max-height: 471.0576923076923px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/out-of-nowhere?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/out-of-nowhere?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Out_of_nowhere"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Therapy_for_product_managers</id><title type="text">Therapy for product managers</title><updated>2020-05-12</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I’ve been busy making a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://producttherapy.show/&#34;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-1456-1456&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F5c307174-e062-4dd8-99bb-171bc2248b5d_6000x6000.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/5c307174-e062-4dd8-99bb-171bc2248b5d_6000x6000.png&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/5c307174-e062-4dd8-99bb-171bc2248b5d_6000x6000.png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:350340,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1456-1456 {
            padding-bottom: 100%;
            padding-bottom: min(100%, 1456px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1456-1456 img {
            max-width: 1456px;
            max-height: 1456px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been a little depressed, infuriated, overwhelmed, grateful, loopy. A real who’s who of feelings. Typical for these days, I imagine, but it had gotten in the way of writing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A significant coping mechanism I’ve embraced during the pandemic is to accept the reality of things, and then avoid thinking about them by doing literally anything else productive with which I can fill time. I started (finally) recording music again. I bought and tinkered with a Raspberry Pi to run more smart home nonsense, a media server, retro games emulator and security camera all in one. My wife and I started a garden. I built a fence around said garden.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had a serious itch for the podcasting game, though, due to my love of hearing people I respect ramble on, unfiltered about really interesting stuff, and the sheer exercise of recording audio. Fortunately my friend and former colleague&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://benerez.com/&#34;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;seemed to as well, and we both had some things to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we started one called&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Product Therapy,&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;which is pretty much what it sounds like: two product guys talking out some things that excite us, frustrate us, and others we can’t really make sense of about the kind of work we’re doing. We noticed that while there are a&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;ton&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;of business, tech &amp;amp; even product-themed podcasts out there, there’s virtually none which get into the&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;really messy stuff&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;about it — the reality of doing the job every day. Everyone seems intent on interviewing leaders of the tech giants, sharing killer insights, and the like.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ll ramble a lot, and we hope you find it entertaining and perhaps helpful (even if you’re not a product manager). It’s available everywhere you find podcasts: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/product-therapy/id1512612390&#34;&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/itunes1512612390/product-therapy&#34;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/show/6ueBiaTEbCssPcb75aC3e6&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=531973&amp;amp;refid=stpr&#34;&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pca.st/0raw1osg&#34;&gt;Pocket Casts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also subscribe directly to our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://producttherapy.show/&#34;&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;page, which is a cool way to directly show your support, plus a way to get members-only episodes if we ever decide to do that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Therapy_for_product_managers"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Clarity_is_out_the_disinfected_window</id><title type="text">Clarity is out the disinfected window</title><updated>2020-03-22</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I am very overwhelmed at the moment and pretty much all the time. Leave it to a global pandemic to cause people to fundamentally reconsider how people work and communicate and live their lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not personally leading a vastly different life compared to how it was two weeks ago: working remote in a farm town with no close friends less than a 45-minute drive away doesn’t really lend itself to lifestyle changes in the face of a highly contagious virus. I’m not even terribly stir-crazy, since our puppy Rosie is getting me outside four to five times a day to urinate, defecate and/or run around the yard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I’m feeling a different stir-craziness, one that is much more psychological. My mind is racing constantly despite multiple attempts to calm it down. I am exhausted at the end of every day, passing out in my bed but somehow waking up feeling poorly rested. It took something like seven attempts to even get this short and not-particularly-groundbreaking post together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I referred back to my “clarity” note which drove my goals for 2020, and pretty much everything is out the window at this point: it’s a struggle to be intentional, I’m not reading, I’m not actively creating, my marriage is strengthening because of the anxiety brought about by a global pandemic, and breathing only helps for a few minutes before this weird reality sets back in. The only thing that is progressing as expected is letting my anxiety about homeownership go, simply because it’s the last thing on my mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am having visceral urges to create &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; but I can’t form a single complete thought around what I could do. It almost feels like the entire world is up for disruption, so there’s a need (or opportunity?) to create things in these trying times, but I can’t achieve the level of mental fortitude required to actually do it. It’s a struggle to come up with an original thought when everyone is seemingly feeling the same: either “I am terrified and confused” or “I refuse to acknowledge this reality.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t really have anything to share for insights, advice, or reflection that hasn’t been already shared. If this experience has taught me anything, it’s that the Internet is wonderful for not feeling alone, but it kind of sucks if you’re feeling the urge to do something original.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But mostly I thought the title of this post was cheeky, and wanted to post it for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=share&amp;amp;action=share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Share tone deaf // color blind&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=share&amp;amp;action=share&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share tone deaf // color blind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Clarity_is_out_the_disinfected_window"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Zoom_is_where_we_hang_out_now</id><title type="text">Zoom is where we hang out now</title><updated>2020-03-13</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I missed my own writing deadline this week. I resolved to post &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; to my newsletter every Monday, and this week I failed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a weird week to think about committing to &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;, to be honest. Everyone’s either in or contemplating a self-quarantine; Alicia and I have basically been quarantining for weeks now. By nature of both of us both working from home, we’re basically mostly at home — save an occasional dog walk or grocery run or outing to a sparsely populated place. Yesterday I did the obligatory bulk-supplies run to BJ’s Wholesale, so now we have months worth of frozen and non-perishable food. Alicia and I have probably spent the majority of our time trying to relax together while acknowledging our crippling anxieties, which in a way has been a bit therapeutic and has certainly brought us together. (That and washing our hands and sanitizing &amp;amp; re-sanitizing our stuff when we forgot to wash our hands before touching something.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel for the folks living alone, working at home alone or generally being stuck inside little boxes in cities, which is where we were only a few months ago. For me, not much has changed since moving out to the sticks: I’ve been working at home, so has my spouse, and neither of us generally go out much between where we live and our anxieties. Alicia has repeatedly stated that, for her, this amount of hand-washing and nervousness and generally trying to avoid crowds is what she’s done for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I am still feeling a bit of the isolation problem that everyone is writing and/or worried about.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s really nice having a wife and puppy at home to love, but there are other people in this world that I like, and my work and hobbies and other distractions only go so far. I’ve FaceTimed a bit with family but that’s differently frustrating. Also frustrating has been my attempts to stay in the loop via social media: a lot of the people I follow seem to be posting a lot about their coronavirus-driven isolation, but it doesn’t feel like we’re doing much about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should we all just get on Zoom calls and hang out, then?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We remote workers have been doing this forever, as a means to build team camaraderie: book a time to jump on Zoom, as a group, and talk about anything &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt; work. We call it, unironically, a Hangout, or sometimes a “coffee chat” but that implies a certain amount of work-ness. A Hangout on the other hand feels like what we do when we go to a bar, or someone’s house, and just – hey – hang out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seriously, though: everyone’s talking about Zoom in the context of remote work, so why not leverage this (or Skype or group FaceTime or pick-your-online-gaming-platform or whatever else) to just hang out with each other? Are people already doing this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m game if you are. I have booze in the house; I’m sure you do too. It’ll kind of be like going to a bar?&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Zoom_is_where_we_hang_out_now"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Earworms</id><title type="text">Earworms suck</title><updated>2020-03-02</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to talk about work or technology or bettering oneself this week. I want to talk about the thing that was stuck in my head for the majority of the past week, which was the following phrase: &lt;em&gt;“We can’t find the books; they must be in La Jolla.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is from a sample used in the song &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/if-not-now-whenever/410842405?i=410842414&#34;&gt;“If Not Now, Whenever” by The Books&lt;/a&gt;, a wonderful experimental folk duo that was moderately popular in hipster circles in the early-mid 2000s. The song itself is fine: pretty repetitive, hypnotic melody, a little boring but also fun for a deep cut. There’s a seemingly random string of voices throughout the song – they don’t tell a story from what I can tell, but the end of one phrase seems to lead into the next. This sample comes up randomly in the middle in the song, after a few old women asking about “the books.” It’s unclear whether this is a meta-reference to the band or a commentary on how people consume media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what else it could be, but the phrase just &lt;em&gt;sounds good&lt;/em&gt; to me. It sits in the rhythm really nicely, and it’s spoken sardonically and cool. It’s not some deeply catchy, intricately-produced melody manufactured to optimize profits; it’s a passing sample likely meant as a joke.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a horrible habit of getting small parts of songs stuck in my head for long periods of time, and then having those songs incessantly distract me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just discovered Poppy, whose whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://pitchfork.com/reviews/albums/poppy-i-disagree/&#34;&gt;vibe and backstory&lt;/a&gt; is insane, and essentially put out a metal record. There are parts of her new album &lt;em&gt;I Disagree&lt;/em&gt; which are certainly catchy, but metal rarely captures my attention these days. I’ve had various parts of &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/concrete/1481273823?i=1481273844&#34;&gt;the lead track “Concrete”&lt;/a&gt; stuck in my head for weeks (something about that “sugar on my teeth” line), and recently became obsessed with the refrain from &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/fill-the-crown/1481273823?i=1481274007&#34;&gt;“Fill The Crown.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back-to-back with Poppy has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/you-make-my-dreams/273750173?i=273750245&#34;&gt;“You Make My Dreams” by Hall &amp;amp; Oates&lt;/a&gt;. Talk about a topic jump: from being ironically buried alive in concrete, I move to a simple love confession. I’ve had this track on-and-off stuck in my head since 2016, when it was on seemingly infinite repeat during my best man’s own bachelor party. There’s no need to explain what makes this song an ear worm: it’s probably stuck in &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; head too from time to time. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.straightdope.com/columns/read/2901/why-do-songs-get-stuck-in-your-head/&#34;&gt;One scientist calls it a “cognitive itch,”&lt;/a&gt; which seems appropriate for this particular track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cognitive itching seems overall appropriate for the whole sensation inspiring this post. Instead of scratching a technical itch or a career itch, I find myself regularly and incessantly scratching sonic itches in my brain. Sometimes this comes to the detriment of one of those other itches; I think my inability to parse Swift documentation and make sense of inexplicable bugs partly relates to my brain being distracted by those melodies and samples that won’t leave.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of these songs &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; incredibly catchy and have fair right to be called earworms, but others get stuck in my head for seemingly no reason whatsoever. I said the word “cocoon” this morning, and now I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/cocoon/20920260?i=20920271&#34;&gt;“Cocoon” by Björk&lt;/a&gt; stuck in my head. It’s not even that catchy of a song; her vocal melodies are usually more meandering than crisp. (This was not written for effect – this specifically happened at 8am this morning, Monday, March 2nd.) I’ve been following the pianist/MC Jason Charles Beck (aka Chilly Gonzales) for a while, and I’ve had his track &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/i-am-europe/962969143?i=962969153&#34;&gt;“I Am Europe”&lt;/a&gt; stuck in my head recently. It’s got a somewhat catchy piano riff, but vocally there’s nothing to hang onto whatsoever: there’s a weird string of spoken-word metaphors in the middle of the song that ring quite hollow (“I’m a dog shit ashtray”; “I’m a toilet with no seat, flushing tradition down”), but the piano line, undercut with pitched moans, just works for me. I haven’t listened to this song or album in years, and there’s no reason for me to either –– it’s not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; great. But it’s in my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the nature of these earworms are subtle and specific. Another song I frequently get stuck in my head is &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/you-with-air/498847282?i=498847285&#34;&gt;“You With Air” by Young Magic&lt;/a&gt;, which is fun and catchy as hell. It shares a vocal line almost identically with &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/grandloves-feat-young-magic/540020916?i=540020924&#34;&gt;Purity Ring’s “Grandloves”&lt;/a&gt;, but I rarely if ever think about that song. I have no idea why, despite having the Young Magic version of the line in my head frequently. The context of the backing rhythm and overall vibe seem to matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It feels narcissistic to get &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/sun-loop/1451324257?i=1451324264&#34;&gt;one of my own songs&lt;/a&gt; stuck in my head, but I have a little guitar and bass line loop stuck in my head. I guess one could call that part of the songwriting process, but this particular loop has been in and out of my head since 2009. I guess you could call it catchy once the vocal melody is attached, but the guitar loop is kind of nothing on its own. I can’t explain it, which I guess is the whole thesis of this post. (I guess it’s also weird to link to said song in my own newsletter. Shameless.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wonder what some earworms tell me about my inner demons. I have a strong distaste for horror movies –– inexplicable gore and chaos make me very uncomfortable –– but sometimes I’ll scratch an aural itch that would be terrifying to most people. Mr. Bungle, a bizarre, fun and sometimes confusing band from the 90s recently announced a small set of reunion shows in California which prompted me to revisit some of their music. I recently got stuck in my head &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/album/carry-stress-in-the-jaw/358575638?i=358575688&#34;&gt;a song of theirs called “Carry Stress In The Jaw”&lt;/a&gt;, a song about grinding one’s teeth during sleep, specifically the jittery saxophone line that begins the song and a bit of the following verse. Any rational person would likely find this song terrifying, between the jarring tonal &amp;amp; genre shifts, the chainsaw-sounding guitars, and Mike Patton’s meandering recitation of an Edgar Allan Poe excerpt which builds to a high-pitched wail. But I find it a fascinating and ultimately entertaining listen, and I apparently get fixated on parts of it from time to time. What does this say about me? The aforementioned Poppy tracks are unconventional and dark but ultimately (as her moniker states –– hey!) poppy and interesting social commentary; “Carry Stress In The Jaw” is chaotic, strange, and sometimes gross without a clear point. Is this a reflection that my mind is in a proverbial gutter? Is this a manifestation of the actual teeth-grinding I do while I sleep? Am I a glutton for aural punishment?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More likely I just am fascinated by sound, but I can’t help but worry about my sanity with a track like this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made a playlist of these songs that I keep pretty up-to-date, for those interested; there’s a lot rattling around in my brain. Check it out &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/playlist/earworms/pl.59ab7b0764e34a45b64984ac80e94ee6&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was fun to write. I didn’t really learn anything for have any nuggets of value to share, but it was nice to shove stressful or effortful things aside and just ramble about songs I like. We should be doing more stuff like this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/302-earworms-suck?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/302-earworms-suck?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Earworms"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Found_my_stuff</id><title type="text">Found my stuff</title><updated>2020-02-24</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m incredibly lucky to have a little bit of time to pursue hobbies or interests outside of my work and family life. One of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/210-everyones-a-workaholic-and-other&#34;&gt;interests I’d been exploring&lt;/a&gt; was app development: I am deeply in love with the iOS/iPadOS ecosystem and have always wanted to tinker within it and contribute to it. Plus, I’d played a little with development before by running a few Wordpress sites in the past, doing low-complexity coding and bug fixes in previous gigs, and spending most of my workweek talking with other developers for a job. &lt;strong&gt;And I had an idea for an app that would actually be useful to me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I tried picking up Swift and SwiftUI to develop said app. After about 10 days I’ve given up. I either don’t have the brain, or the patience, for software development. I get the model-view-controller framework completely – I need to at least &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; this concept to do my day job, but while I can sort of read code, it’s a whole order of magnitude of complexity for me to write it &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; not run into a dozen build failures or inexplicable crashed. The place where I got stuck, specifically, was around supporting Siri Intents: the idea involved needing to talk to Siri, or build Shortcuts, around locating a specific piece of data, and I got incredibly frustrated trying to figure this out. &lt;a href=&#34;https://atp.fm/episodes/363&#34;&gt;Tech pundits are right when they say Apple’s documentation is not useful&lt;/a&gt;, and I don’t have the skillset to adapt examples from other people to my own use cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea stuck, though. It came out of an episode of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/+E5INvkfOI/10:17&#34;&gt;wonderful &lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/+E5INvkfOI/10:17&#34;&gt;Reconcilable Differences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/+E5INvkfOI/10:17&#34;&gt; podcast&lt;/a&gt;. In this episode (“Squirrel List”), John Siracusa talks about his use of Apple Notes to keep a running list of where random things are in his house. Turns out I could have used one of those: &lt;strong&gt;My wife and I move random items around the house regularly and then forget where we put them.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of these are easy to track down, such as AirPods or our phones, because we can yell out to Siri and then a loud bell will be emitted from said device. I wanted to be able to yell out to Siri, “Where’s my goddamn box cutters?” when I have a dozen cardboard boxes to break down and can’t find them. The only options I could think of were to buy a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thetileapp.com/&#34;&gt;Tile&lt;/a&gt; or wait for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macrumors.com/guide/airtags/&#34;&gt;Apple’s competing product&lt;/a&gt;, but I also don’t want to spend hundreds (possibly thousands) of dollars putting a Bluetooth tracker on all my tools, random cables, passport, etc. Not to mention all the &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2018/11/01/bleedingbit-security-flaws-bluetooth-wireless-networks/&#34;&gt;problems&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.foxnews.com/tech/turn-off-your-bluetooth-warn-security-experts&#34;&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/bluetooth-complex-security-risk/&#34;&gt;security&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.healthline.com/health-news/are-wireless-headphones-dangerous#Scientists-believe-the-current-EMF-guidelines-are-inadequate&#34;&gt;electromagnetic radiation in the house&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So instead of frustrating myself endlessly trying to build a swanky app to solve this problem and then monetizing it for no good reason, I built a group of shortcuts to help me with keeping track of shit around the house.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Found It, the shortcut suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collectively they’re called &lt;strong&gt;Found It&lt;/strong&gt;, and they enable you to securely tell Siri where your stuff is around the house. When you can’t find one of those things, just ask Siri and she’ll tell you. If you put that thing somewhere else, just tell Siri and she’ll remember next time you can’t find it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you like, you can tap on the links below to download Found It and all its components:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/934134a4d9d041bf887295cb53e9a7ca&#34;&gt;Found It&lt;/a&gt; (the master Shortcut, which does everything)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/1a70d1021e8643bab99a0c68481f8efc&#34;&gt;Keep Track of Something&lt;/a&gt; (just asks Siri to track something new)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/04f01a26eb474a89b42a9bc683c13d10&#34;&gt;Help Me Find Something&lt;/a&gt; (just asks Siri to look up where something is)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/81941086663b44249bc4266ac47fa012&#34;&gt;I Moved Something&lt;/a&gt; (just tells Siri the new location of something)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;From there, you can start tracking your own stuff. These shortcuts also support custom inputs, so you can make your own mini-Shortcuts that ask Siri for a specific item (so you don’t have to re-specify every single time). For example, I made a shortcut to ask Siri “Where’s the hammer?” since I keep leaving my hammer in random places around the house, and she’ll just tell me that. You can get that example &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/f20812149ab5454db4800a0ec570323d&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;; you’ll just need to tell Siri where your hammer is first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The master shortcut is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://routinehub.co/shortcut/4636&#34;&gt;RoutineHub&lt;/a&gt;, which is a community and directory of crazy-powerful Shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If this is interesting to you, let’s talk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve realized over the past week that Shortcuts creation is basically a lightweight form of programming, and it’s proven very helpful in the solving of everyday problems around the house. I’m going to be writing more about my explorations here (like some people are already doing – see &lt;a href=&#34;http://macstories.net/shortcuts&#34;&gt;Federico Viticci&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewcassinelli.com/&#34;&gt;Matthew Cassinelli&lt;/a&gt; for just two great examples). If you have a problem you need solving and I might be able to help you solve it with a Shortcut, or if you just find this interesting, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:brandonlucasgreen@gmail.com&#34;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; or subscribe to this newsletter. Thanks for listening!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Sign up now&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sign up now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Found_my_stuff"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/So,_layoffs_are_weird</id><title type="text">So, layoffs are weird</title><updated>2020-02-17</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.boston.com/news/business/2020/02/13/wayfair-layoffs&#34;&gt;my previous employer laid off roughly 3% of its staff&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of people lost jobs, and I personally worked with about two dozen of them and knew those folks pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;😞&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to pretend that this was a massively unexpected surprise; this is absolutely something that happens with over-hiring and sketchy management of performance for large groups of skilled employees. I’m surprised it hadn’t happened already, to be completely honest. But I can’t ignore the fact that layoffs are a really weird/sad thing and I’ve been thinking about it more than I care to in the past few days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Layoffs are especially weird in 21st-century society, in that we’re able to easily rally for each other on a social network and get out of laid-off status in a matter of hours. I posted twice on LinkedIn offering to help or talk to anyone affected by the layoffs, and these were &lt;em&gt;by far&lt;/em&gt; the most popular posts I’ve ever made on a social network, ever. Not only did laid-off folks appreciate it (I spend much of yesterday afternoon responding to folks looking for tips on remote work), but dozens of former colleagues, current colleagues and people I’ve never met liked and commented on what I had to say. Most of those people also had their thing to say, and most of the thoughts were exactly the same: offers to help or talk, the processing of “many feelings” with ultimate optimism and gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It almost feels compulsory, that you &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; post about one of these things because everyone else in your circle is already doing it: if you’re not grateful to the employer that laid you off, you’re an ass. That compulsory feeling leads it the emotions almost feeling fake. I genuinely do want to help because I think a lot of highly-skilled and intelligent people aren’t aware of the possibilities out there beyond open office environments at well-intentioned-but-sometimes-overzealous e-commerce companies. I also want to make sure folks are okay with expressing frustration or constructive criticism at their previous employers, because without that it’s hard to imagine companies getting smarter about how they hire and evaluate the need for teams &amp;amp; individuals if everyone’s grateful for the company that took away their lifeline on a moment’s notice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bostonglobe.com/2020/02/13/business/these-people-will-have-jobs-two-weeks-if-they-want-them/&#34;&gt;At least people come together to help each other in the face of a bad situation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I saw some recruiter posting about a job fair for the folks affected, and his post mentioned layoffs at another company. I then started digging and realized just how many companies – large, highly-reputed, tech companies – are growing too quickly or cannot meet the demand of the market in which they compete. &lt;a href=&#34;https://patch.com/massachusetts/needham/tripadvisor-layoff-200-workers&#34;&gt;Tripadvisor had layoffs last month&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bizjournals.com/boston/news/2019/04/23/more-layoffs-at-athenahealth.html&#34;&gt;AthenaHealth did last year&lt;/a&gt;, so did &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bizjournals.com/boston/news/2019/01/18/state-street-to-lay-off-1-500-in-turn-toward.html&#34;&gt;State Street&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/logmein/comments/f2j390/annual_layoffs/&#34;&gt;there are rumors flying around that LogMeIn also did&lt;/a&gt; recently. Turns out dozens of Boston-based companies have had pretty major layoffs in the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another friendly reminder that the primary goal of these businesses is to grow and profit, and the care of its employees over time becomes pretty secondary. If you can find a place where you’re felt taken care of well enough, then good on you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to be helpful in a way that doesn’t feel alienating to someone. Here’s an attempt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some advice to anyone who was surprised by it: pay more attention to your employer’s hiring goals, earnings calls, performance review process and the perceived performance of those around you. You’ll quickly realize that there’s plenty of places from which to trim fat in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or here’s some other advice that I’m perpetually working on myself: make it so that a layoff doesn’t affect you that much. This can be done in multiple ways, but here are three I’ve really focused on:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pay very close attention to how your current or next employer runs things: how it spends money, its hiring goals, how it runs performance evaluations, where its profits come from. Ask questions if you don’t understand things or don’t find the information you’re looking for. If you can’t get answers, think about why you’re not getting answers. Ideally, you’ll find a company that is clear with how it runs things and that aligns with your values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be confined by where you live. Yes, relocation can be hard, but also, &lt;strong&gt;remote work is very much a thing that you should not ignore&lt;/strong&gt;. A quick search with the right keywords (think “remote [position] jobs”) will net you some interesting stuff to consider. If you like being in an office, coworking spaces do exist, and some companies will even cover this expense if you play your cards right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build up safety nets in other work, and, if you can, find a job that will enable you the time to do this. This is the classic &lt;em&gt;side hustle&lt;/em&gt; argument. Most people I know who work in tech are so consumed by their work that it feels impossible to make time to do things on the side. My advice? Unless you truly love your work, don’t work for companies that consume you. My previous employer was one of those, and while I loved the work for a long time, once I stopped loving it I needed to get out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ll stop talking now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/So,_layoffs_are_weird"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Everyone&#39;s_a_workaholic_and_other_related_concerns</id><title type="text">Everyone’s a workaholic &amp; other related concerns</title><updated>2020-02-10</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, Valentine’s Day week. May you all purchase for your significant others a greeting card as mushy as the one I purchased for mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of my theme of &lt;strong&gt;clarity&lt;/strong&gt; has involved figuring out how I use my time &amp;amp; tools: deleting apps and accounts that don’t add value, keeping an accurate calendar, setting deliberate goals for my interests &amp;amp; projects and seeing how I move those forward. I’ve attempted and failed at time tracking three times already this year (probably due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/fits-starts&#34;&gt;my comfort in scattered focus&lt;/a&gt;), but I don’t feel the need for it &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of the clarity I’m bringing to the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; behind what I choose to do. I want to pursue a lot of scattered interests, and this clarity is helping me pick one to focus on when I’m bored or unsure, which is helpful because the list is long:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write more music for solo piano&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Listen to more music with intentional focus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regularly write and grow a newsletter (hey!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write a speculative fiction novel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn Swift and make 1 of 3 different iOS app ideas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bunch of DIY projects around the house&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find opportunities to automate things around the house&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start a punk band&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buying and building a few Lego sets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;And probably others I can’t think of at the moment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were multiple nights in January and early February during which I &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; to work on one of those things I resolved to start doing this year, but sometimes one just wants to watch a wonderful television show or spin a record. But there persists a nagging feeling. An itch not being scratched.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of itches. One involves forming chords on a piano keyboard, another involves what you’re reading right now, several require spending money, most involve just building &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; cool. I’m not a skilled programmer, but I’ve wanted to become good at it so I could eventually make a product on my own. And then I realized that &lt;strong&gt;#nocode&lt;/strong&gt; is a thing: No-code development, the idea (or now a movement, I guess) that there are dozens of cheap, scalable services out there on the Internet now which can be strung together to form a meaningfully viable business operation. I could spin up an idea of my own in a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As per usual I’m incredibly late to the party: Personalities on Twitter spinning out consulting services to help fellow no-coders, whole premium communities where indie hackers bounce ideas and team up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of passion in those forums. But that passion seems as much about the money as the idea. It almost sounds desperate sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am grateful that while I have lots of itches I’m trying to scratch, I don’t feel &lt;em&gt;desperate&lt;/em&gt; to pursue them. I’m not truly sure if others feel that way, but the Internet sure makes it feel like it. Everyone in my social circle is hustling, peddling, working. Pretty much all the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just isolated to LinkedIn or weird, specialty forums: it seems to have taken over Instagram. I have reached the point where Facebook’s own app — yes, the app that my mother and her friends use more than people my own age — is more useful to me than Instagram. I swore off Facebook years ago: it had not been on my phone since 2017 I believe, and I used to only visit Facebook to un-check an occasional box that I didn’t realize was checked that was sending me an email. But since moving to a town where meaningful news and activity gets conducted on Facebook, I’ve had to reinstall it. It’s how I know whether my trash pickup will happen. It’s how I know whether there are emergency road closures due to weather. It’s how I know whether there are bobcats roaming in our local area from which I should keep my puppy away. I even get some nice family-centric updates in my news feed which I’ve carefully pruned to avoid political dross. I’ve received value by completely disabling virtually all other content in Facebook’s ecosystem from showing up, but even the occasional one that does is almost a reprieve from the workaholism I’m seeing elsewhere. Example: Facebook seems to be the only place I can see friends from high school talking about their kids and family — &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; their work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instagram, on the other hand, has devolved into nothing more than &lt;em&gt;escapes that no longer work for me&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;entities trying to convince me to buy their shit&lt;/em&gt;. I’m now numb to beautiful photos of landscapes, home interiors and adorable pets — or, more likely, it’s impossible to feel that escape when every fourth story is a sponsored ad and 50+% of the escapist photos are really just graphics supporting a call to sign up or buy. (My wife’s Instagram feed is even worse.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s extending into the real world. My wife and I need to make a conscious effort &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to talk shop while eating meals. I consciously decided to move my blog to Substack because they make it really easy to monetize one’s writing. Irony.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where does it stop, though? Everyone’s always asked the obligatory “What do you do?” as an ice-breaker, but we don’t seem to need it anymore because well just yell what we do at each other because we need to just to get by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talking only about your work all the time can’t be good for us. It must &lt;em&gt;inherently&lt;/em&gt; add massive stakes to virtually every conversation you have; the discourse becomes centered on your income, your lifeblood. Sure, eventually &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of those side hustles could become sustainable, zero-maintenance, passive income, and that’s the dream. But think about the psychological damage this is probably giving us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No wonderful mindfulness apps are so popular: it’s not that they’re fashionable, it’s that all of us are regularly on the verge of a psychotic break.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I truly hope my fellow millennials have hobbies they can pour this anxiety into. &lt;strong&gt;The beauty of a hobby is that, if I lose interest, or if my interest changes shape, there are no psychological stakes.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure, a hobby might become a money pit but at least it’s on your own volition. I can morph that hobby as I please and as my passion for it changes. The problem with all this hustle is that, even if you try an idea and it doesn’t work, you are &lt;em&gt;compelled&lt;/em&gt; to move onto the next thing. Sure, you can take a break and watch a few episodes of [insert HBO or Netflix show], but that may come at a price of either active or dormant anxiety. I know this to be true because my wife struggles with this constantly as a self-employed person, and we’re doing pretty okay financially. What about everyone that isn’t?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am incredibly grateful that I landed a fairly steady job where I can be impactful and do somewhat interesting work for solid pay. I am also grateful for the music industry’s collapse and subsequent homogenization, because it painfully forced me to become comfortable with treating my expensive academic vocation as a hobby and pivot to something more stable. When I decided to stop exploring music as a profession, it didn’t stop me from playing; when I decided &lt;a href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/peak-live-music-or-no-more-surprises&#34;&gt;I no longer enjoy live music&lt;/a&gt;, I kept recording music and listening to recorded music. I listen to new and old music constantly; I strive to engage in deep conversations around why great music is great. But I gave up on trying to make money on it, and it’s no longer a stress point in my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Then again, maybe I should be trying to make money on that interest: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strongsongs.libsyn.com/website&#34;&gt;I could have easily done something like this&lt;/a&gt;. There’s the fucking itch again, and here comes the psychotic break.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’m just overblowing this in my head. But I don’t think this internal swirl of frustration and concern for my fellow compulsive hustlers is misplaced. The feeling is exacerbated, too, because I don’t know what I can do to help, or even if the help is actually needed. Some people &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the hustle, even though it burns me out and it occasionally cripples people I love with anxiety. There is only so much I can do to productively add to the world, tune out the noise in it, and focus on those I truly care about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have no other conclusion than that. Perhaps also I wish Lego sets were cheaper because then I’d just build those all night after a hard day’s staring at a laptop screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-1092-1456&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fbf2f5269-d2b7-4ee1-9443-01c62777c67d_4032x3024.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/bf2f5269-d2b7-4ee1-9443-01c62777c67d_4032x3024.jpeg&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/bf2f5269-d2b7-4ee1-9443-01c62777c67d_4032x3024.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1092,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:3801057,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1092-1456 {
            padding-bottom: 75%;
            padding-bottom: min(75%, 1092px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1092-1456 img {
            max-width: 1456px;
            max-height: 1092px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I apologize if that came off as angsty or from a place of privilege. Here’s to another week of trying to suck a little less in a world of chaos.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Everyone&#39;s_a_workaholic_and_other_related_concerns"/></entry></feed>