<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">Blog - brandon lucas green</title><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Blog</id><updated>2020-03-22</updated><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Blog"/><icon>https://brandonlucasgreen.comstatic/favicon.jpeg</icon><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Clarity_is_out_the_disinfected_window</id><title type="text">Clarity is out the disinfected window</title><updated>2020-03-22</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I am very overwhelmed at the moment and pretty much all the time. Leave it to a global pandemic to cause people to fundamentally reconsider how people work and communicate and live their lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not personally leading a vastly different life compared to how it was two weeks ago: working remote in a farm town with no close friends less than a 45-minute drive away doesn’t really lend itself to lifestyle changes in the face of a highly contagious virus. I’m not even terribly stir-crazy, since our puppy Rosie is getting me outside four to five times a day to urinate, defecate and/or run around the yard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I’m feeling a different stir-craziness, one that is much more psychological. My mind is racing constantly despite multiple attempts to calm it down. I am exhausted at the end of every day, passing out in my bed but somehow waking up feeling poorly rested. It took something like seven attempts to even get this short and not-particularly-groundbreaking post together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I referred back to my “clarity” note which drove my goals for 2020, and pretty much everything is out the window at this point: it’s a struggle to be intentional, I’m not reading, I’m not actively creating, my marriage is strengthening because of the anxiety brought about by a global pandemic, and breathing only helps for a few minutes before this weird reality sets back in. The only thing that is progressing as expected is letting my anxiety about homeownership go, simply because it’s the last thing on my mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am having visceral urges to create &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; but I can’t form a single complete thought around what I could do. It almost feels like the entire world is up for disruption, so there’s a need (or opportunity?) to create things in these trying times, but I can’t achieve the level of mental fortitude required to actually do it. It’s a struggle to come up with an original thought when everyone is seemingly feeling the same: either “I am terrified and confused” or “I refuse to acknowledge this reality.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t really have anything to share for insights, advice, or reflection that hasn’t been already shared. If this experience has taught me anything, it’s that the Internet is wonderful for not feeling alone, but it kind of sucks if you’re feeling the urge to do something original.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But mostly I thought the title of this post was cheeky, and wanted to post it for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=share&amp;amp;action=share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Share tone deaf // color blind&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/?utm_source=substack&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_content=share&amp;amp;action=share&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share tone deaf // color blind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Clarity_is_out_the_disinfected_window"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/So,_layoffs_are_weird</id><title type="text">So, layoffs are weird</title><updated>2020-02-17</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.boston.com/news/business/2020/02/13/wayfair-layoffs&#34;&gt;my previous employer laid off roughly 3% of its staff&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of people lost jobs, and I personally worked with about two dozen of them and knew those folks pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;😞&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to pretend that this was a massively unexpected surprise; this is absolutely something that happens with over-hiring and sketchy management of performance for large groups of skilled employees. I’m surprised it hadn’t happened already, to be completely honest. But I can’t ignore the fact that layoffs are a really weird/sad thing and I’ve been thinking about it more than I care to in the past few days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Layoffs are especially weird in 21st-century society, in that we’re able to easily rally for each other on a social network and get out of laid-off status in a matter of hours. I posted twice on LinkedIn offering to help or talk to anyone affected by the layoffs, and these were &lt;em&gt;by far&lt;/em&gt; the most popular posts I’ve ever made on a social network, ever. Not only did laid-off folks appreciate it (I spend much of yesterday afternoon responding to folks looking for tips on remote work), but dozens of former colleagues, current colleagues and people I’ve never met liked and commented on what I had to say. Most of those people also had their thing to say, and most of the thoughts were exactly the same: offers to help or talk, the processing of “many feelings” with ultimate optimism and gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It almost feels compulsory, that you &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; post about one of these things because everyone else in your circle is already doing it: if you’re not grateful to the employer that laid you off, you’re an ass. That compulsory feeling leads it the emotions almost feeling fake. I genuinely do want to help because I think a lot of highly-skilled and intelligent people aren’t aware of the possibilities out there beyond open office environments at well-intentioned-but-sometimes-overzealous e-commerce companies. I also want to make sure folks are okay with expressing frustration or constructive criticism at their previous employers, because without that it’s hard to imagine companies getting smarter about how they hire and evaluate the need for teams &amp;amp; individuals if everyone’s grateful for the company that took away their lifeline on a moment’s notice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bostonglobe.com/2020/02/13/business/these-people-will-have-jobs-two-weeks-if-they-want-them/&#34;&gt;At least people come together to help each other in the face of a bad situation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I saw some recruiter posting about a job fair for the folks affected, and his post mentioned layoffs at another company. I then started digging and realized just how many companies – large, highly-reputed, tech companies – are growing too quickly or cannot meet the demand of the market in which they compete. &lt;a href=&#34;https://patch.com/massachusetts/needham/tripadvisor-layoff-200-workers&#34;&gt;Tripadvisor had layoffs last month&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bizjournals.com/boston/news/2019/04/23/more-layoffs-at-athenahealth.html&#34;&gt;AthenaHealth did last year&lt;/a&gt;, so did &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bizjournals.com/boston/news/2019/01/18/state-street-to-lay-off-1-500-in-turn-toward.html&#34;&gt;State Street&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/logmein/comments/f2j390/annual_layoffs/&#34;&gt;there are rumors flying around that LogMeIn also did&lt;/a&gt; recently. Turns out dozens of Boston-based companies have had pretty major layoffs in the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another friendly reminder that the primary goal of these businesses is to grow and profit, and the care of its employees over time becomes pretty secondary. If you can find a place where you’re felt taken care of well enough, then good on you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to be helpful in a way that doesn’t feel alienating to someone. Here’s an attempt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some advice to anyone who was surprised by it: pay more attention to your employer’s hiring goals, earnings calls, performance review process and the perceived performance of those around you. You’ll quickly realize that there’s plenty of places from which to trim fat in a pinch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or here’s some other advice that I’m perpetually working on myself: make it so that a layoff doesn’t affect you that much. This can be done in multiple ways, but here are three I’ve really focused on:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pay very close attention to how your current or next employer runs things: how it spends money, its hiring goals, how it runs performance evaluations, where its profits come from. Ask questions if you don’t understand things or don’t find the information you’re looking for. If you can’t get answers, think about why you’re not getting answers. Ideally, you’ll find a company that is clear with how it runs things and that aligns with your values.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be confined by where you live. Yes, relocation can be hard, but also, &lt;strong&gt;remote work is very much a thing that you should not ignore&lt;/strong&gt;. A quick search with the right keywords (think “remote [position] jobs”) will net you some interesting stuff to consider. If you like being in an office, coworking spaces do exist, and some companies will even cover this expense if you play your cards right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build up safety nets in other work, and, if you can, find a job that will enable you the time to do this. This is the classic &lt;em&gt;side hustle&lt;/em&gt; argument. Most people I know who work in tech are so consumed by their work that it feels impossible to make time to do things on the side. My advice? Unless you truly love your work, don’t work for companies that consume you. My previous employer was one of those, and while I loved the work for a long time, once I stopped loving it I needed to get out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ll stop talking now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/So,_layoffs_are_weird"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Everyone&#39;s_a_workaholic_and_other_related_concerns</id><title type="text">Everyone’s a workaholic &amp; other related concerns</title><updated>2020-02-10</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello, Valentine’s Day week. May you all purchase for your significant others a greeting card as mushy as the one I purchased for mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part of my theme of &lt;strong&gt;clarity&lt;/strong&gt; has involved figuring out how I use my time &amp;amp; tools: deleting apps and accounts that don’t add value, keeping an accurate calendar, setting deliberate goals for my interests &amp;amp; projects and seeing how I move those forward. I’ve attempted and failed at time tracking three times already this year (probably due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/fits-starts&#34;&gt;my comfort in scattered focus&lt;/a&gt;), but I don’t feel the need for it &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of the clarity I’m bringing to the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; behind what I choose to do. I want to pursue a lot of scattered interests, and this clarity is helping me pick one to focus on when I’m bored or unsure, which is helpful because the list is long:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write more music for solo piano&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Listen to more music with intentional focus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regularly write and grow a newsletter (hey!)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write a speculative fiction novel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn Swift and make 1 of 3 different iOS app ideas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bunch of DIY projects around the house&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find opportunities to automate things around the house&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start a punk band&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buying and building a few Lego sets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;And probably others I can’t think of at the moment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There were multiple nights in January and early February during which I &lt;em&gt;wanted&lt;/em&gt; to work on one of those things I resolved to start doing this year, but sometimes one just wants to watch a wonderful television show or spin a record. But there persists a nagging feeling. An itch not being scratched.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of itches. One involves forming chords on a piano keyboard, another involves what you’re reading right now, several require spending money, most involve just building &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; cool. I’m not a skilled programmer, but I’ve wanted to become good at it so I could eventually make a product on my own. And then I realized that &lt;strong&gt;#nocode&lt;/strong&gt; is a thing: No-code development, the idea (or now a movement, I guess) that there are dozens of cheap, scalable services out there on the Internet now which can be strung together to form a meaningfully viable business operation. I could spin up an idea of my own in a weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As per usual I’m incredibly late to the party: Personalities on Twitter spinning out consulting services to help fellow no-coders, whole premium communities where indie hackers bounce ideas and team up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of passion in those forums. But that passion seems as much about the money as the idea. It almost sounds desperate sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am grateful that while I have lots of itches I’m trying to scratch, I don’t feel &lt;em&gt;desperate&lt;/em&gt; to pursue them. I’m not truly sure if others feel that way, but the Internet sure makes it feel like it. Everyone in my social circle is hustling, peddling, working. Pretty much all the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn’t just isolated to LinkedIn or weird, specialty forums: it seems to have taken over Instagram. I have reached the point where Facebook’s own app — yes, the app that my mother and her friends use more than people my own age — is more useful to me than Instagram. I swore off Facebook years ago: it had not been on my phone since 2017 I believe, and I used to only visit Facebook to un-check an occasional box that I didn’t realize was checked that was sending me an email. But since moving to a town where meaningful news and activity gets conducted on Facebook, I’ve had to reinstall it. It’s how I know whether my trash pickup will happen. It’s how I know whether there are emergency road closures due to weather. It’s how I know whether there are bobcats roaming in our local area from which I should keep my puppy away. I even get some nice family-centric updates in my news feed which I’ve carefully pruned to avoid political dross. I’ve received value by completely disabling virtually all other content in Facebook’s ecosystem from showing up, but even the occasional one that does is almost a reprieve from the workaholism I’m seeing elsewhere. Example: Facebook seems to be the only place I can see friends from high school talking about their kids and family — &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; their work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instagram, on the other hand, has devolved into nothing more than &lt;em&gt;escapes that no longer work for me&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;entities trying to convince me to buy their shit&lt;/em&gt;. I’m now numb to beautiful photos of landscapes, home interiors and adorable pets — or, more likely, it’s impossible to feel that escape when every fourth story is a sponsored ad and 50+% of the escapist photos are really just graphics supporting a call to sign up or buy. (My wife’s Instagram feed is even worse.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s extending into the real world. My wife and I need to make a conscious effort &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to talk shop while eating meals. I consciously decided to move my blog to Substack because they make it really easy to monetize one’s writing. Irony.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where does it stop, though? Everyone’s always asked the obligatory “What do you do?” as an ice-breaker, but we don’t seem to need it anymore because well just yell what we do at each other because we need to just to get by.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talking only about your work all the time can’t be good for us. It must &lt;em&gt;inherently&lt;/em&gt; add massive stakes to virtually every conversation you have; the discourse becomes centered on your income, your lifeblood. Sure, eventually &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; of those side hustles could become sustainable, zero-maintenance, passive income, and that’s the dream. But think about the psychological damage this is probably giving us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No wonderful mindfulness apps are so popular: it’s not that they’re fashionable, it’s that all of us are regularly on the verge of a psychotic break.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I truly hope my fellow millennials have hobbies they can pour this anxiety into. &lt;strong&gt;The beauty of a hobby is that, if I lose interest, or if my interest changes shape, there are no psychological stakes.&lt;/strong&gt; Sure, a hobby might become a money pit but at least it’s on your own volition. I can morph that hobby as I please and as my passion for it changes. The problem with all this hustle is that, even if you try an idea and it doesn’t work, you are &lt;em&gt;compelled&lt;/em&gt; to move onto the next thing. Sure, you can take a break and watch a few episodes of [insert HBO or Netflix show], but that may come at a price of either active or dormant anxiety. I know this to be true because my wife struggles with this constantly as a self-employed person, and we’re doing pretty okay financially. What about everyone that isn’t?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am incredibly grateful that I landed a fairly steady job where I can be impactful and do somewhat interesting work for solid pay. I am also grateful for the music industry’s collapse and subsequent homogenization, because it painfully forced me to become comfortable with treating my expensive academic vocation as a hobby and pivot to something more stable. When I decided to stop exploring music as a profession, it didn’t stop me from playing; when I decided &lt;a href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/peak-live-music-or-no-more-surprises&#34;&gt;I no longer enjoy live music&lt;/a&gt;, I kept recording music and listening to recorded music. I listen to new and old music constantly; I strive to engage in deep conversations around why great music is great. But I gave up on trying to make money on it, and it’s no longer a stress point in my life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Then again, maybe I should be trying to make money on that interest: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strongsongs.libsyn.com/website&#34;&gt;I could have easily done something like this&lt;/a&gt;. There’s the fucking itch again, and here comes the psychotic break.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’m just overblowing this in my head. But I don’t think this internal swirl of frustration and concern for my fellow compulsive hustlers is misplaced. The feeling is exacerbated, too, because I don’t know what I can do to help, or even if the help is actually needed. Some people &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the hustle, even though it burns me out and it occasionally cripples people I love with anxiety. There is only so much I can do to productively add to the world, tune out the noise in it, and focus on those I truly care about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have no other conclusion than that. Perhaps also I wish Lego sets were cheaper because then I’d just build those all night after a hard day’s staring at a laptop screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-1092-1456&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fbf2f5269-d2b7-4ee1-9443-01c62777c67d_4032x3024.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/bf2f5269-d2b7-4ee1-9443-01c62777c67d_4032x3024.jpeg&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/bf2f5269-d2b7-4ee1-9443-01c62777c67d_4032x3024.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1092,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:3801057,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1092-1456 {
            padding-bottom: 75%;
            padding-bottom: min(75%, 1092px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1092-1456 img {
            max-width: 1456px;
            max-height: 1092px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I apologize if that came off as angsty or from a place of privilege. Here’s to another week of trying to suck a little less in a world of chaos.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Everyone&#39;s_a_workaholic_and_other_related_concerns"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Clarity_check-in</id><title type="text">Clarity check-in</title><updated>2020-02-03</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;And here’s month two. There’s a beautiful partly sunny sky outside but I’m instead staring at an iPad screen. Just kidding, I’m oscillating between the two because the outside is nice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My theme of the new year was about striving for &lt;strong&gt;clarity&lt;/strong&gt;, and reflecting on the first month of the new decade, forced weekly writing seems to be helping achieve this. I have a bit more clarity around how and why I think about things, what things I want to spend time thinking about, and how I want to convey them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing I’m not thinking about is the Super Bowl, which is a waste of my time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a few larger topics I’m noodling on for future posts, but for now I have some updates on how the year is going so far, and some things I’ve enjoyed along the way. If you want to follow along with my future updates, please: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Sign up now&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sign up now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not doing things is doing things&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I did write down some resolutions-of-sorts back on New Year’s Day, in the spirit of that theme. A few are progressing fairly well: writing regularly, being more present for my wife, stopping &amp;amp; breathing more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Others… well, I have enough clarity to know I don’t care to move those forward at the moment. They’re simply not &lt;em&gt;as&lt;/em&gt; important to me as the ones in focus right now. These are things I’m not doing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participating in a band/musician/songwriting group.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ll probably write more about this later, but I’ve been rethinking what kind of music I want to make after becoming inspired more by ambient &amp;amp; solo piano music than recent popular music. This is an area for which I am working toward clarity but haven’t gotten there yet. Once I figure this out, I’ll explore this or whether it’s even going to add value to my music composition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding something with which to spoil myself.&lt;/strong&gt; I wrote this down at the behest of my wife who suggested I should do more for myself, and I agreed, but this has been difficult to give priority. I honestly feel like getting a puppy was a splurge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultivating an online base/community/whatever.&lt;/strong&gt; I see this newsletter as something to contribute here, but also I simply don’t care too much to self-promote — I’d rather just write what I feel and see if it sticks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading regularly.&lt;/strong&gt; I started a fiction book and it’s at my bedside, and every time I go to read it I’m asleep in five minutes. Damn you, &lt;a href=&#34;http://avocadogreenmattress.com/&#34;&gt;comfortable mattress.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;One area I’m still working through is &lt;strong&gt;more strategically defining my relationship with capital-w Work.&lt;/strong&gt; Working remotely is wonderful and I’ve even grown comfortable with &lt;a href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/fits-starts&#34;&gt;being a bit scattered about it&lt;/a&gt;, but I realized early this year that I was so excited about remote work that I neglected to think about what &lt;em&gt;else&lt;/em&gt; I might want out of my job. To me, this is not about leaving my job for something better (because no job is perfect but working for Abstract is quite great), but ensuring that I’m being clear, proactive and assertive about what I expect out of the job and how I want to shape it. I’m circling around this idea now, and not sure how it will work out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick aside: “Stay tuned” is an obsolete phrase and let’s stop saying it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was about to end that last paragraph with “Stay tuned.” It felt immensely weird to say that, for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I loathe the idea of demanding my tiny reader base to be attentive to my bullshit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I publish my next update, an email will appear in your inbox. You don’t need to stay tuned at all; it will just appear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Stay tuned” is no longer a thing we need to do because, unless you’re on cable TV, our technology no longer warrants it. From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/Are-there-any-alternatives-to-the-phrase-stay-tuned?share=1&#34;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back in the day of radio broadcasting, before the era of automatic frequency control (in the radio tuner) a station would ‘drift’ and the listener would have to move the tuner dial ever so slightly to hear the station loud and clear (remember the strength and clarity call out 5 by 5, in which each was evaluated on a 1 to 5 scale, with 5 being the best). Atmospheric propagation would also cause the station to surge and fade at times. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;…Now enter the role of the sponsors of the radio program. Each sponsor would be billed a certain amount based on the number of “ears” that the program would “deliver”. If the number of listeners dropped, the sponsor would pay less and the radio stations income would also drop. It was certainly in the radio stations best interest for listeners to stay tuned to the program - and it would sometimes take a dedicated effort on the part of the listener to ‘stay tuned’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Internet people: Let’s stop saying this, k? It’s not relevant for our medium. Honestly, it makes us sound desperate for someone’s attention. Might as well say “don’t forget about me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BoJack Horseman is over and I’m sad, plus other recent great TV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of TV, I’ve started to more deliberately watch TV less and at specific times, which has admittedly been a challenge because &lt;em&gt;there’s so much damn good TV.&lt;/em&gt; Just in the past 1–2 weeks, here’s what I’ve enjoyed a lot:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BoJack Horseman&lt;/em&gt;, season 6 part 2. This has been arguably my favorite show of the 2010s, and I’m sad to see it go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New Pope&lt;/em&gt;. The pace is slow, but the cinematography is beautiful and the premise is incredibly interesting to watch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Servant&lt;/em&gt;. I haven’t enjoyed psychological thrillers much lately, but this one has just enough to keep intrigued, between the creepy nanny and the amazing food/cooking shots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Broad City&lt;/em&gt;. This isn’t new and I loved this show when it was current, but Alicia and I began rewatching it as the show we could use to laugh out loud when no other show would… including &lt;em&gt;The Good Place&lt;/em&gt; which ended strong but not hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed a recurring theme in these shows as being powerful and immersive, but still escapist. &lt;em&gt;Little America&lt;/em&gt; on Apple TV+ &lt;em&gt;seemed&lt;/em&gt; good, but it’s too real-world (and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/28/21110838/little-america-review-apple-tv-plus-immigrant-stories-anthology&#34;&gt;somehow feels problematic despite the intent&lt;/a&gt;) for me to enjoy right now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you like these recommendations and general thoughts, please:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/203-clarity-check-in?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Share&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/203-clarity-check-in?&amp;utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=share&amp;action=share&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Share&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambient Essentials is the best playlist for not being distracted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best thing — no surprise — has been shutting off the TV and instead listening to music. Turns out when something isn’t visually distracting you, you’re less distracted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I truly madly deeply love music, but sometimes it’s also distracting. The one exception that has one-hundred-percent delivered on not distracting is Apple Music’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/playlist/ambient-essentials/pl.472dc0c5efe548bb9846e484378aa47b&#34;&gt;Ambient Essentials&lt;/a&gt; playlist. This is a wonderful mix of highly repetitive, calming pieces that both engross me and allow time to pass without me even noticing. Case &amp;amp; point: William Basinski’s forty-minute-long “dlp 6” and Ekkehard Ehlers&#39; heartbreaking “Plays John Cassavetes II.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, also, sorry — not a Spotify user. &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/6ZcP3X4ANIWPFuDUpGhcbu&#34;&gt;There’s a comparable playlist there&lt;/a&gt;, though, for all you folks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fewer tools, the better&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macstories.net/stories/my-must-have-apps-2019-edition/2/#content&#34;&gt;Viticci has been discussing recently&lt;/a&gt;, and Merlin Mann so eloquently put in &lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/b2w/462&#34;&gt;a recent episode of Back to Work&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve felt a higher degree of clarity by resorting to basics instead of elaborate tools &amp;amp; systems when it comes to my devices &amp;amp; apps. I first tackled this for my online presence, which is no longer beholden to unreliable web hosting providers, and simpler too as a result. I already tweeted about this, so in the spirit of not repeating myself:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tweet&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://twitter.com/sphmrs/status/1218983110521622529?s=21&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;full_text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Late to this, but being an individual online is so cheap in 2020 thanks to &lt;span class=\&amp;quot;tweet-fake-link\&amp;quot;&gt;#nocode&lt;/span&gt;. I can have a cohesive personal brand that hooks into all the networks for basically $20/year if I wanted.  (1/3)&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;username&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;sphmrs&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;brandon lucas green&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;date&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Sun Jan 19 19:46:35 +0000 2020&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;photos&amp;quot;:[],&amp;quot;quoted_tweet&amp;quot;:{},&amp;quot;retweet_count&amp;quot;:1,&amp;quot;like_count&amp;quot;:9,&amp;quot;expanded_url&amp;quot;:{}}&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sphmrs/status/1218983110521622529?s=21&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tweet-header&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;tweet-user-avatar&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/twitter_name/w_36/sphmrs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter avatar for @sphmrs&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;tweet-author-name&#34;&gt;brandon lucas green &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;tweet-author&#34;&gt;@sphmrs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Late to this, but being an individual online is so cheap in 2020 thanks to &lt;span class=&#34;tweet-fake-link&#34;&gt;#nocode&lt;/span&gt;. I can have a cohesive personal brand that hooks into all the networks for basically $20/year if I wanted.  (1/3)&lt;div class=&#34;tweet-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;tweet-date&#34;&gt;January 19th 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;retweets&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;rt-count&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; Retweet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;likes&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;like-count&#34;&gt;9&lt;/span&gt; Likes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest burden w/r/t tools has been how I plan &amp;amp; keep track of what I need to do every day. For a while I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://culturedcode.com/things&#34;&gt;Things&lt;/a&gt; to meticulously organize &amp;amp; track those things. It’s a beautiful and quite capable app, but it overwhelmed me constantly. So I pulled everything out of it and moved it all into &lt;strong&gt;stock Apple Reminders and Notes&lt;/strong&gt;. I was already using these to share basic lists with my wife (groceries, shopping, some house project stuff), and when I realized I &lt;em&gt;don’t need to hold myself to arbitrary deadlines for most things in my personal life&lt;/em&gt;, I realized the incredibly simple ecosystem I had for myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things that &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; take place on a day or at a time are in my calendar. I religiously use calendar notifications, even for personal deadlines like posting this newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things I need reminders about end up in Reminders (crazy). I don’t need a special methodology to organize and categorize those things to do. Notes acts as a reference, a system of record, things I occasionally need to look up: like house utility information, useful shortcuts tips, gift ideas. Sure, I could categorize and tag these things incessantly, but I can also just search for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything that isn’t obviously a task needing a reminder or a reference note starts in &lt;a href=&#34;http://getdrafts.com/&#34;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt;, which is the one exception to this first-party rule. I like Drafts for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capturing an idea reliably from my Apple Watch is the best thing, and Drafts is the most reliable way to do this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This app can format, merge move and prepare text for use literally anywhere, including &lt;a href=&#34;http://substack.com/&#34;&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt; (on which this newsletter is hosted), which has neither an app or an API.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Virtually everything in this app can be organized as I like and done in one click or keyboard shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drafts plays the role of my &lt;strong&gt;daily agenda&lt;/strong&gt;, not unlike the pen-and-paper planners folks used to (and still?) use. I wrote a Shortcut that pulls reminders and events taking place today and organizes it all into a Draft — I run this every morning as part of a larger routine that shuts off the alarm system and turns on a few lights downstairs, so it’s ready for me as I’m starting the day. This prepared draft aggregates everything I need to do, everything that’s going on, into a single sheet. With the Taskpaper format, I can easily cross things off the list or add notes to go through later. For reminders that come up throughout the day, I can also check those off when the notification hits, or I can sync a matching thing on my Agenda back over and kill the reminder if I no longer need it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is still evolving — in some ways Reminders feels redundant with Drafts for things that are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; time-sensitive, so I might move some of my generic lists over to Drafts, which seems like a common use case for this app. That said, simplifying how I go through my day has helped me take better notes while also feeling less overwhelmed or distracted by apps. It’s also been a fun tinkering exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a link to the Shortcut, in case it’s helpful to you: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/540f08daaeb04bf0816517621ba36452&#34;&gt;Prep Daily Agenda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-1017-1456&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F7c20e9b6-d376-4817-bb43-6a1c112bdde7_2388x1668.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/7c20e9b6-d376-4817-bb43-6a1c112bdde7_2388x1668.png&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/7c20e9b6-d376-4817-bb43-6a1c112bdde7_2388x1668.png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1017,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:964146,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/png&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1017-1456 {
            padding-bottom: 69.8489010989011%;
            padding-bottom: min(69.8489010989011%, 1017px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1017-1456 img {
            max-width: 1456px;
            max-height: 1017px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s all I’ve got. Bye!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Clarity_check-in"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Thoughts_on_thoughts_on_iPads</id><title type="text">Thoughts on thoughts on iPads</title><updated>2020-01-29</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;They say that if you force a regular habit of writing, good things happen. In that sense I should have posted this on Monday; damn you, life and your sudden obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year was the tenth anniversary of the iPad, and a lot of people wrote about it. A lot of it was purely reflective, but some folks evaluated whether the iPad was a success in those ten years. It’s undeniably a success from a sales perspective, but lots of people seem focused on the question of whether it was&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;transformative&lt;/strong&gt;: to the way we do computing, to the landscape of technology businesses, to the way people live their lives. There are a lot of ways in which a technology can be transformative, but much of the more critical chatter has been on whether it&#39;s been transformative to the way we work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Gruber suggests that&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/2020/01/the_ipad_awkwardly_turns_10&#34;&gt;the iPad has drastically failed to significantly change industries like the Mac did ten years into its existence, largely due to weaknesses in software interaction design, specifically multitasking&lt;/a&gt;. This didn&#39;t sit well with me, and it took me a few days sitting with my iPad Pro to figure out why: mainly that comparing the trajectory of iPad in the 2010s to Mac in the 80s/early 90s feels like a fundamentally fraught, apples-to-oranges comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no mention of the fact that&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Apple computers in the 80s and 90s had no obvious device competition in the market at the time&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;and thus the 10-year anniversary is an unfair comparison to give to the iPad. Solutions for designers effectively did not exist like they did once Adobe&#39;s products for the Mac started coming out, and the iPad needed to compete with two other major ecosystems made by Apple itself: the Mac and the iPhone. We&#39;re still seeing how the iPad fits into the larger ecosystem, but it&#39;s already clear that it&#39;s part of a larger picture, one where all types of work can be done on a suite of devices, each perfectly suited to the task at hand, rather than on a computing device at all. If anything, the type of transformation the iPad begat is different than that of the Mac: where the Mac redefined industries, the iPad helped to redefine the consumer technology ecosystem as being universal and multi-device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We could talk about work &amp;amp; industry changes, but there is little discussion about the changes iPad is bring to&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;how creators make things&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;how students learn.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;I believe that iPad’s contribution in these areas are massive, even if not single-handedly, because they (and netbooks) have made full-on computing affordable to more people. There are countless examples showcasing and communities built around the iPad for&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thesweetsetup.com/using-ipad-photography-workflows/&#34;&gt;photography&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cultofmac.com/592572/ipad-music-production/&#34;&gt;music production&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.audiob.us/&#34;&gt;live music performance&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techradar.com/how-to/mobile-computing/tablets/how-to-write-a-novel-on-an-ipad-1300438&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;. Sure, these may be more incremental in terms of technological changes, but the iPad has put those capabilities in the hands of more people, without professional training or large budgets, and enabling them to do those things anywhere. Sure,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcworld.com/article/2855768/why-chromebooks-are-schooling-ipads-in-education.html&#34;&gt;Chromebooks are probably used more widely in schools&lt;/a&gt;, but without iPads, would there have been the same competitive push for Google to develop an extremely-low-cost netbook for students?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While multi-tasking on iPad does have issues, I disagree that it is fundamentally broken and I consider it a distraction from the main goals the iPad intends to achieve. I personally believe these interactions quite close and the issues I’ve experienced feel more like bugs and solvable with small improvements. I use multi-tasking almost every day on my iPad and, thanks likely to a bit of muscle memory and self-education. Ten years into the Mac, designers were using Macs for work, but it&#39;s 2020 and I know hundreds of people who still struggle with their Macs and PCs but live and die by their iPads because of how much more intuitive it is for them (again, likely due to the learning curve being lessened by iPhones, but that should not diminish the importance of iPads).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not really directly relevant, but something I think about a lot: since social media took over most discourse about technology, it seems that most people&#39;s opinions on virtually anything is perceived as more extreme (especially in the negative) than it was in the 90s. We could very well be dinging the iPad and feeling nostalgic about the impact of previous technological innovations because technological innovation is everywhere all the time and everyone&#39;s senses are being numbed all the time by vitriol nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laying all this out, I still do feel like the iPad has a long way to go.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;But this feels empirically exciting to me in a way that Macs won&#39;t ever feel anymore.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;It seems unfair — almost unsafe — to hold technologies created nearly 30 years apart to the same rubric, as it runs the risk of dismissing technologies that could be changing the lives of many.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days, I use my iPad for virtually every bit of computing in my life with three exceptions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using and testing&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://abstract.com/&#34;&gt;the product I manage for my job&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking music ideas to finished product in Logic Pro X, which might become unnecessary over time; and&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Running a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://homebridge.io/&#34;&gt;Homebridge&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;server&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I distinctly use it for the following things:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing and publishing said writing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking unstructured ideas and fleshing them out&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Planning my days, nights and weekends&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Communication that&#39;s more than 1-2 sentences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Viewing and editing photos&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting, and sometimes finishing, song productions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All my daily work for my job except for software testing (which, by the way, I can technically do on an iPad via a secure VNC connection to my MacBook Pro for work)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sure, I could be doing all these things on a Mac (or even an iPhone if I wanted to destroy my hands), but I don&#39;t have to. I can do these things anywhere thanks to a cellular connection, hyperportability, perfectly-tailored apps, and a beautifully designed interface whose quirks are no more problematic than those of any other computing device. And to me, that&#39;s transformative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-1092-1456&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ff06978b4-be5e-4a80-9747-6c6bc9d9281f_4032x3024.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/f06978b4-be5e-4a80-9747-6c6bc9d9281f_4032x3024.jpeg&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/f06978b4-be5e-4a80-9747-6c6bc9d9281f_4032x3024.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1092,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:2395594,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;image/jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1092-1456 {
            padding-bottom: 75%;
            padding-bottom: min(75%, 1092px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1092-1456 img {
            max-width: 1456px;
            max-height: 1092px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;See y&#39;all next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Thoughts_on_thoughts_on_iPads"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/A_bunch_of_crap_duct-taped_together</id><title type="text">A bunch of crap duct taped together</title><updated>2020-01-20</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s Martin Luther King Jr. Day, and I have four unused Philips Hue bulbs and I don&#39;t know what to do with them. I bought them for a previous apartment, in which I really wanted to play with Apple&#39;s HomeKit protocol as a means to automatically dim the lights when it&#39;s bed time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My new house warranted different lights to achieve the same result, and these became redundant. I wanted to use these leftover bulbs — the basic white ones — for the ceiling fan in our living room. However, the previous owners of the house put in a combination fan/light dimmer switch, and when the dimmer and smart bulbs interact with each other, the bulbs flicker annoyingly. I could replace that switch, but to do so the right way and keep smart bulbs in play, I&#39;d need to convert the one combo switch into two separate switches (one for light, one for fan) because there is no HomeKit-compatible combo switch on the market (or any smart switches of this nature that I&#39;ve been able to find).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s no sense using them in the basement. There are already lights down there, and I go down once a week to make sure there are no leaks or ghosts or anything, and then I come right back up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not worth trying to use them in the garage, where the ceiling nearly twenty feet high and I don&#39;t own a ladder with which I can reach it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t use them in the office (or rather, the spare bedroom with a desk in it). I don&#39;t have the desk space for a table lamp, and if I put them in the ceiling then they&#39;ll be on the main light switch and I don&#39;t want to deal with HomeKit errors when I accidentally shut the switch off. If I do use them in the ceiling fixture, then I&#39;d need to either have them run on a motion sensor that detects when I&#39;m in the room and train myself to stop using the switch, or replace the switch with a smart one which is more money blown on this stupid pointless really fun experiment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should I just buy some floor lamps as an excuse to use the bulbs? This option seems very dumb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of these options create more work and don&#39;t solve any additional problems without said work. I could argue that this is a fun, mildly inexpensive hobby, but it&#39;d be an incredibly first-world hobby. It would also be one my wife loathes because of how often I&#39;m tinkering with it, and inadvertently breaking things like our security system or the bedside table lamps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in previous writings of mine, I&#39;ve tried various means to get the things in my life working for me. Instead, they create more dependencies and problems to solve. The house we bought came with Wifi-enabled garage doors, and I bought a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://simplisafe.com/&#34;&gt;SimpliSafe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to secure the house. Neither system is HomeKit-compatible, so I jerry-rigged them into the Home app thanks to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://homebridge.io/&#34;&gt;Homebridge&lt;/a&gt;, which required me to first invest in and learn how to run a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;because I didn&#39;t want to have a server running 24/7 on my Mac, and then once I got the Raspberry Pi set up, I needed to figure out how to set up Homebridge, get an externally-accessible IP address, figure out how to do SSH so&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/p/running-a-dumb-robot-vacuum-with-shortcuts&#34;&gt;I can run the robot vacuum&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;since I can’t get&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;reliably running through Homebridge, maybe set up an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://plex.tv/&#34;&gt;optional Plex server&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;now that the Raspberry Pi is actually working, make sure I don’t break Homebridge in the process of setting up Plex, test, test again, test some more, sit down and play with my garage doors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think I’ve opened the garage doors twice with my iPhone since setting this up, but when I do, it works great. I do occasionally check the SimpliSafe sensors and set it at night, but a frustrating rate-limit issue on their API causes this to break occasionally and requires me to reset the Homebridge server — which I then built a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/guide/shortcuts/welcome/ios&#34;&gt;Shortcut&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to do in two taps rather than needing to SSH into the aforementioned Raspberry Pi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Takes a breath)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I want to believe that this crazy set of dependencies into which I’m throwing myself is unique to the new and exciting Internet of Things. It’s incredibly nerdy and fun, but it’s a lot of work with questionably payoff. But most of my early adventures in homeownership are proving to require a similar network of dependencies, sometimes optional, mostly required because of reasons I’m not always able to challenge. And occasionally I question the payoff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alicia and I wanted to redo the floors in the new house because we had some money left over from our house budget. This was a glorious proposition: we came in way under budget on the purchase and could start turning our moderately-sized house in the sticks into a dream home that would make Pinterest proud. In reality, it’s three months later and the floors are still not completely done, we can’t get them finished until the contractor we hired gets stair parts stained to match the actual flooring, for which he had to sub-contract a different company who effectively gave up on the job, thus requiring us to have to find a second sub-contractor to finish the child task for the parent flooring project which is actually the second phase of an even larger flooring project. All of this because we did not know that flooring manufacturers apparently don’t make stair parts that match their own flooring, despite it likely being a very common use case to install matching stairs and floors. (That seems like bad business. Is that bad business? I don’t even know.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6Rw0qWJFJs/&#34;&gt;The adorable little puppy we just got&lt;/a&gt;? Even she came with a bunch of things to remember. This isn’t a surprise: dogs are living things. But it’s also basically an entirely new set of commitments and optional-but-strongly-recommended-by-the-rescue-shelter-and-vet activities that somehow also depend on each other. First, these pills, then wait six days then start giving her three pills. Then, another test and maybe she’ll be ready to start training and play school but only if this is all done before she is five months old; if it takes longer, we have to do a different set of things. Day two of owning a dog felt like I just absorbed an entire team at work, and that team was sort of floundering but didn’t really realize they were floundering because they didn’t know any better.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s weird: being a guy who helps build products, I thrive on figuring out &amp;amp; squashing dependencies. And I’ve gotten pretty great at doing so in the last few years of my career.&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;It’s incredibly overwhelming, with that in mind, to have introduced so many dependencies into my life all at once with little idea how to tackle them.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;These things start to feel like a bunch of crap duct-taped together, despite a ton of prep (and money — let’s be honest) to avoid that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I’ve started to treat my dependencies like enemies, such that I keep them real close. I actively look for them, I embrace them when I find them. I question why something seems to come together so easily. Sometimes this creates a small anxiety, but I’ve trained my brain to mostly treat these as learning experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example: I replaced a dumb light switch with a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B071RFYQFM/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o02_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&#34;&gt;HomeKit-compatible dimmer switch&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the first time last week. The next morning, we had a weird series of brownouts in the house. I immediately thought I caused it with my hackery, until twenty minutes later when I decided to check the electric company’s website which confirmed a regional outage. Power returned fifteen minutes after that. Sigh of relief: it wasn’t my fault, and now I know that my electricity provider can sometimes screw up the voltage in my house.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time to figure out what the hell it’s going to take to put in a backup power generator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, some of these things are worth the trouble. Here’s what makes them so:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-1941-1456&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fd3c49cd5-4cec-49c7-9e1d-902986cec17b_4032x3024.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/d3c49cd5-4cec-49c7-9e1d-902986cec17b_4032x3024.jpeg&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/d3c49cd5-4cec-49c7-9e1d-902986cec17b_4032x3024.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1941,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1941-1456 {
            padding-bottom: 133.31043956043956%;
            padding-bottom: min(133.31043956043956%, 1941px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1941-1456 img {
            max-width: 1456px;
            max-height: 1941px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;image-link image2 image2-1941-1456&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://cdn.substack.com/image/fetch/f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fbucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Ff48fd274-61a2-4699-a1e2-5139713fdced_3024x4032.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/f48fd274-61a2-4699-a1e2-5139713fdced_3024x4032.jpeg&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;src&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://bucketeer-e05bbc84-baa3-437e-9518-adb32be77984.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/f48fd274-61a2-4699-a1e2-5139713fdced_3024x4032.jpeg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;height&amp;quot;:1941,&amp;quot;width&amp;quot;:1456,&amp;quot;resizeWidth&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;bytes&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;alt&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:null,&amp;quot;href&amp;quot;:null}&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;style&gt;
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1941-1456 {
            padding-bottom: 133.31043956043956%;
            padding-bottom: min(133.31043956043956%, 1941px);
            width: 100%;
            height: 0;
          }
          a.image2.image-link.image2-1941-1456 img {
            max-width: 1456px;
            max-height: 1941px;
          }
        &lt;/style&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course I&#39;m rambling about smart home stuff on an actually important holiday like Martin Luther King Jr. Day. If you read through this whole thing, do yourself a favor and do something nice in the name of universal civil rights, like a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://action.aclu.org/give/now&#34;&gt;donation to the ACLU&lt;/a&gt;. Or&amp;nbsp;subscribe to this, because it’s another newsletter to entertain you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;button-wrapper&#34; data-attrs=&#34;{&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Sign up now&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;:null}&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;button primary&#34; href=&#34;https://tonedeafcolorblind.substack.com/subscribe?&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sign up now&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See you next time!&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/A_bunch_of_crap_duct-taped_together"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Secret_weird_things_I_do</id><title type="text">Secret weird things I do</title><updated>2020-01-13</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite podcasts is&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/rd/&#34;&gt;Reconcilable Differences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which is a biweekly conversation between two parents in tech/podcasting about their lives. It’s a huge inspiration for this blog.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a recurring segment the two hosts (John Siracusa and Merlin Mann) talk about called “Secret Weird Things People Do,” in which they talk about just that — not just confessing to the things they do, but also dig into where the weird thing came from, why they do those things, whether it’s actually weird or pretty normal, and the like. I find these discussions incredibly interesting and compelling and humbling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In that spirit, here is a list of some secret weird things I do:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I cannot let my kitchen get messy, and if I do, it viscerally bugs me to the point of a near-anxiety attack. This is especially problematic since my wife is an Italian who leaves a huge mess in her wake when she cooks. Typically at meal time, I am cleaning up as she is making messes — much to her frustration, since sometimes I inadvertently wash dishes she is still using. If we are hosting people for dinner, I will try to escape the conversation to clean up the kitchen — also to the frustration of my wife.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If I need a reminder to do something (say, in an app), I can’t just take it down. I&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;to pick a time and appropriate category/list for that thing, even if it’s neither easily categorizable nor time-sensitive. Sometimes this bites me when I get a reminder at a horribly inopportune time, but it’s the only way I know how to keep track of things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ask me to do something, I can’t listen to the next thing you have to say until I write that ask down. Due to the previous weird thing, this might take me an extra second and I’m sorry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I compulsively look for things to automate, organize or optimize in my home, even if it’s a negative return on investment. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/rd/121&#34;&gt;Merlin talked about this in a recent episode.&lt;/a&gt;) I spent an absurd amount of time trying to correctly place speakers around our house for audio playback. I rearrange my iOS device home screens almost daily — not for fun, but because I think I’m missing something by how they’re arranged. I track my dog’s bowel movements in a Numbers spreadsheet. I’ve set up part of my home to be smart and I’m not sure it was worth it, but it keeps feeling like something I must do. Sometimes this extends into my wife’s stuff, and she usually gets frustrated with me. I’ll probably write more about each of these weird things later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I compulsively use GPS in my car even when I three-hundred-percent know where I am going and there is no possibility of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t bite my nails, but I pick at them compulsively. Alicia loathes it and slaps/pinches me to get me to stop. I&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;this used to be a nervous tick, but now it just happens constantly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If there is a stack of books (or book-shaped things like laptops/iPads), I must have them perfectly aligned in the stack. If there is a book in the pile that is slightly rotated, I must rotate it so all the edges are aligned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite a lot of my cleanliness-related weird things, I don’t seem to be bothered by objects covered in dust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are these things actually weird? Do other people do weird things like this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Secret_weird_things_I_do"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Fits_and_starts</id><title type="text">Fits &amp; starts</title><updated>2020-01-06</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, it’s 2020 now! Cue things about resolutions and intentions and bettering selves. This year I intend to drive for more clarity and intentionality with what I put out to the world and how I spend my time doing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At work, most of us try to optimize how we spend our working time using a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;http://getclockwise.com&#34;&gt;Clockwise&lt;/a&gt;. It enables you to set preferences for how &amp;amp; when you like to work, automatically scans everyone’s calendars for meetings, and automatically reschedules those meetings to give each participant as much “focus time” based on their own preferences. On the surface, it’s wonderful for creating meeting block periods without having to think about arranging my day, and some of my colleagues thrive in long periods of deep focus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I barely use the focus time as Clockwise probably intends. Being at home, even in a relatively bare spare room / office space, I’m constantly distracted by my personal life: &lt;a href=&#34;http://aliciagreen.co&#34;&gt;my wife&lt;/a&gt;, our things, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/B6Rw0qWJFJs/&#34;&gt;new puppy&lt;/a&gt;, my Nintendo Switch, my Apple Music library, Wikipedia, trees, cars driving by, a lightning strike of an idea, snacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a while this frustrated me. I had thought working from home was the ultimate path to deep focus and productivity: no commute, no distractions by coworkers, no proverbial watercooler to seek out gossip (though I do enjoy my kitchen), no weird internal IT rules that prevent me from running my work computer the way I want. But I still find myself distracted, often by my own bullshit, which results in a very fits-and-starts style of work through much of the workday. Twenty minutes of deeply focused writing or backlog admin might be suddenly interrupted by my own desire to update &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.apple.com/us/playlist/cooking-music/pl.u-BMWzVFrq3kg&#34;&gt;my near-perfect playlist to cook to&lt;/a&gt;. Alicia might suddenly be having an awful symptom flare-up and I now suddenly need to make lunch and find her medication. Having a puppy isn’t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; like having children, but it’s certainly tested my ability to context switch on a dime to avoid pee stains all over the house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve very recently learned to accept this reality of working.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s okay to get distracted by life. It’s okay to feel a little bored &lt;a href=&#34;http://abstract.com&#34;&gt;trying to improve how teams design products&lt;/a&gt; after hammering away at a product requirements document for a bit. It’s okay to stop and cuddle with my wife or a dog because that provides me so much more joy and fulfillment than how much time I can put into staring at a laptop screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can still be quite intentional even if I’m bouncing between the many things in my life in fits &amp;amp; starts. An optimally-placed three hour block of time to write a song or a strategy document won’t solve for me being clear in what I’m looking to do and why; I can be comfortable working ten minutes here, ten minutes there, as long as I know why I’m doing it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Fits_and_starts"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/An_extremely_good_problem_to_have</id><title type="text">An extremely good problem to have</title><updated>2018-08-26</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just ended my one-year expat assignment for my company. I’m back in the US, most likely for good — so long, massive weekend farmer’s markets and cheap healthcare; hello political malaise and smartphone convenience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was in Berlin, my job was very specific to the European market and required a deep embedding into European office culture. A lot of the standard corporate tropes apply — abundant meetings, open office environment, good-and-bad stakeholders to manage — but knowing how to navigate the interpersonal relationships and cultural nuances of an office is best done by immersing oneself in that office. Doing the same job from remote is, in a 8,000+ person company, difficult to sustain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So now I’m in transition. Still at the same company, but looking for something to take on next as I phase out of my current responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This has led to a very interesting phenomenon: &lt;strong&gt;a whole lot of teams seem to want me.&lt;/strong&gt; I have spent roughly 30% of my last week simply meeting new people and learning about other problem spaces going on within the company, to see if they are interesting and impactful for me to take on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While in many parts of both the US and the larger world people are constantly finding themselves out of work, struggling to make end’s meet, I’m having no less than 6 unique jobs thrown at me (disclaimer: all at the same company) with a crazy amount of enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is an extremely good problem to have, and something I have weird feelings about.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t love saying “no” despite having to do this a lot in my job. This is that same problem, but at a meta-level to product management — for the roles I don’t take, it’s: “Sorry, I don’t find your problem interesting enough to take a full-time salaried position to go solve.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve underestimated how many interesting product management problems there are at a Big E-Commerce Company. It calls into question why I spent over 3 years in largely the same space — doing different things, in different markets (and spending a full year living in a different market). But could I have been even happier by looking for these opportunities earlier on? Why aren’t some departments more proactive about showcasing their problems &amp;amp; solutions to attract people?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How firm of a decision do I really _need_ to make? If I pick a role that I like on paper and end up disliking, how easy is it to recall these same opportunities I’m currently being presented with?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider the bargaining-chip aspects of my position. If so many people want me, can I make them fight for me? How much of _that_ am I willing to push for, as opposed to simply being happy in my next position?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I realize these are extremely first-world questions to be asking. I am in an amazing position. But decisions are hard. And while it’s probably all going to be fine regardless of which path I take, I desperately want it all to be fine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/An_extremely_good_problem_to_have"/></entry><entry><id>https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Adventures_in_remote_desktopping</id><title type="text">Adventures in remote desktopping</title><updated>2018-05-22</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love working on an iPad Pro. It’s the device that I find myself wanting to continually pick up, and the device on which I seem to get the most done — not always finished products, but the best and most fully defined ideas I can &lt;em&gt;usually&lt;/em&gt; bring to reality. That goes for many aspects of my life: personal projects to cultivate my relationship with &lt;a href=&#34;http://laviecreative.co/&#34;&gt;my wife&lt;/a&gt;, writing and producing the bulk of &lt;a href=&#34;http://brandonlucasgreen.bandcamp.com/&#34;&gt;songs&lt;/a&gt;, writing and communicating and planning product ideas and larger initiatives for my job, writing this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My job is doing product management which, while a very complex and multi-faceted job, is essentially reading, writing and talking. &lt;strong&gt;Hey now — the iPad is amazing for that. &lt;/strong&gt;I’ve got Slack, Outlook, the Google Suite of apps, my writing and task management apps of choice loaded up, and that makes up about 90% of the job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other 10%? Fairly technical stuff locked down to company-owned devices. I’m diagnosing issues with complex operational products, testing features, writing SQL queries, reading code — stuff that would be insane for a large public e-commerce company to leave open.To do &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; work, I am effectively locked into a Windows PC. At least it’s a massively souped-up quad core Windows 10 PC, but…it’s a PC. Stuck between the Google and Office ecosystems. Locked down by IT administrators. This PC is a laptop attached to an enormous dock connected to two Dell monitors in a corner of a big room, neither of which I use or maintain a consistent connection to said enormous dock. Because PC laptop keyboards seem to be all-encompassingly awful, I have a separate, wired external keyboard and (also wired) mouse which still hurt my hands to use, just slightly less so than the laptop keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All to do about 10% of my job. Possibly less on some days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the iPad just sits there, next to said collection of heavy, bulky metal objects connected by many thick cables, waiting eagerly for me to return to the other 90% of my job.I was recently thinking about why I bother using the PC at all. I don’t mean this to undervalue our IT department, but &lt;strong&gt;what does it mean to be a primary working machine in the first place?&lt;/strong&gt; Can I just pretend that my primary work machine is my iPad Pro, and the PC is just a novelty device that I bring in as &lt;em&gt;the big guns&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or, could I rely on VNC/remote desktop access for the few things I need the PC for? For a long time, I honestly forgot this was a thing: you could access your desktop computer, in its entirety, from another device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turns out &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Remote Desktop&lt;/strong&gt; on iOS isn’t half bad at all — and since my work machine runs Windows 10, it’s all tablet friendly (thanks Surface) and my sensitive work stuff translates nicely to a 10.5” tablet. I can tap to execute a script, or open a Chrome bookmark, or run a POST request in Postman, or…open a 80MB Excel worksheet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have three main gripes with this approach, which keeps me occasionally reluctantly returning to my PC:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;iOS’s stock keyboard doesn’t seem to like unicode quotation marks — ‘ and ‘, but not `’`. I find myself copying-and-pasting quotation marks around SQL queries, which can become annoying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since Windows uses different conventions for key commands, and you’re accessing Windows via an iPad, sometimes basic key commands are hard to get right. The basics (Select All + Copy + Paste) work fine, but Windows-app-specific ones do not. I sometimes find myself needing to use a combination of hardware keyboard and Microsoft RD’s built-in software keyboard just to reopen a recently closed tab in Chrome-within-Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Slides and Sheets (not Docs) are pretty terrible on iOS, so I sometimes need to use Remote Desktop for &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;. It’s sometimes actually more effective than the native app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Temporary sanity&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve drastically undervalued remote desktop access, and now have an even deeper appreciation for both my iPad and Microsoft’s investment in the iOS ecosystem. It is now &lt;em&gt;even&lt;/em&gt; easier to do my job from anywhere, even if that job is locked into certain systems and processes for various reasons.\&lt;/p&gt;</content><link href="https://brandonlucasgreen.com/Adventures_in_remote_desktopping"/></entry></feed>